Spice for the front page, isn't it?
香料的頭版，不是嗎？
All you can think of are headlines for the front page.
所有你能想到的都為頭版頭條。
Oh, drop it!
噢，砸！
Here comes Judge Raghunath.
這裡談到拉古納特法官。
Such a gentleman! Why on earth did that goon want to kill him?
這樣一個紳士！到底為什麼那呆子要殺死他？
Here comes your friend.
這裡談到你的朋友。
Is the jury in place? - Yes, my Lord. Present.
到位陪審團？ - 是的我的主。當下。
Is the accused present? - Present, my Lord.
在被控禮物？ - 現在，我的上帝。
Who is the counsel for the accused?
誰是被告律師？
Have you no lawyer to defend your case?
你有沒有律師為其辯護你的情況？
In that case, the government... - My Lord.
在這種情況下，政府...  - 我的主。
I'm the counsel for the accused.
我對被告律師。
I do not wish to defend myself.
我不想為自己辯護。
I promised to defend you, if you're ever arraigned. Remember?
我答應你辯護，如果你曾經過堂。記得？
Does the accused give his consent?
難道被告給他的同意？
Yes.
是。
Raj, you have been accused of a murderous attack on Judge Raghunath.
拉吉，你一直在指責法官拉古納特一個兇殘的攻擊。
You may plead your case.
你可以懇求你的案件。
I swear to speak the truth.
我發誓說真話。
Judge Raghunath, can you tell us why the accused tried to kill you?
拉古納特法官，你能告訴我們為什麼被告試圖殺了你？
Did he have any enmity with you?
他有沒有跟你打任何敵意？
Yes. The grudge that a born felon bears...
是。一個天生罪犯承擔鬥氣...
against the judge who sentences him and grants no reprieve.
對法官判決誰他和贈款沒有死緩。
Could there be no other reason for such animosity?
難道還有沒有其他原因，這樣的仇恨？
None. How else could I relate to him?
沒有。我還能有別的可能涉及到他嗎？
I have no further questions.
我沒有進一步的問題。
Defense may proceed with cross-questioning.
國防部可能會盤問進行。
Judge, you are senior to me.
法官，你是我年長。
If in the course of questioning, I happen to affront you do forgive me.
如果在訊問的過程中，我碰巧冒犯你原諒我。
Someone's life is at stake. And you have taught me...
一個人的生命危在旦夕。你教我...
to ignore all relationships for the dispensation of justice.
無視正義的豁免所有關係。
This is my first interrogation. Please give me your blessings.
這是我第一次審訊。請給我你的祝福。
What do you mean when you call the accused a born felon?
你是什​​麼意思，當你調用被告一個天生的罪犯做？
He has been a tramp and a hoodlum...
他一直是一個流浪漢和一個流氓...
ever since he was a child. His record says it.
自從他還是個孩子。他的記錄說，這。
This penchant for crime has surely been transmitted congenitally.
這種傾向犯罪肯定已經被先天傳輸。
Judge, do you have any children?
法官，你有孩子嗎？
No
沒有
But how is this question relevant to this case?
這是怎麼回事的問題有關這個案子？
Most relevant. Think again. Are you certain that you have no children?
最相關。再想一想。你確定你有沒有孩子？
No. But I reiterate. This question... - Can you recount the circumstance...
不可以，但我要重申。這個問題...  - 你能講述的情況下...
when you threw your wife out of your house?
當你把你的妻子你的房子嗎？
My Lord, am I to be forced to reply to such meaningless questions?
我的主人，我是被迫回答這樣的問題毫無意義？
Ms Rita, you may ask questions relevant only to the case.
麗塔女士，你可能會問只與案件的問題。
We wish to know whether or not, the accused attempted murder.
我們希望知道與否，被告企圖謀殺。
If yes, then why?
如果是的話，為什麼？
Enough! Stop it! I'm a murderer! Hang me if you will!
足夠！停下來！我是兇手！如果你將掛起我！
Order! Order!
訂購！訂購！
Proceed with your questioning.
與你的問話繼續。
The accused does not deny having assaulted Judge Raghunath.
被告並不否認有毆打法官拉古納特。
But, as you said just now, the question is why he did it.
但是，正如你剛才說的，問題是他為什麼這樣做。
This interrogation is meant to reveal the answer...
這審訊是為了揭開謎底......
if you my Lord, and Judge Raghunath repose your trust in me for a while
如果你是我的主，拉古納特法官寄託你的信任，我一會兒
You may proceed.
您可能會繼續進行。
I repeat my question. Can you recount the circumstance...
我重複我的問題。你可以講述的情況下...
when you threw your wife out of your house?
當你把你的妻子你的房子嗎？
I beg your pardon, Judge Raghunath, but this question is very important.
不好意思，拉古納特判斷，但這個問題是非常重要的。
And not only for the accused. For you too.
不僅為被告。對你來說太。
The cause of whatever is happening today, lies rooted in your past.
無論是今天發生的原因，就在於植根於你的過去。
Remember?
記得？
Can you tell us? Why, when and under what circumstance...
你能告訴我們嗎？為什麼，什麼時候，在什麼情況下？
did you throw your wife out of your house?
你把你的妻子你的房子嗎？
Why, when and under what circumstance...
為什麼，什麼時候，在什麼情況下？
..did you throw your wife out of your house?
..did你把你的妻子你的房子嗎？
24 years ago...
24年前...
I was practicing law in Lucknow.
我是在勒克瑙律師執業。
I was the black sheep of the family, because I opposed social norm...
我是家裡的害群之馬，因為我反對社會規範...
and I had married a widow. My father was a big gun.
我嫁給了一個寡婦。我的父親是一個大槍。
And was away in Bombay most of the time. He was unhappy with me.
而遠在孟買的大部分時間。他不高興我。
But under no circumstance, was I willing to leave Leela.
但在任何情況下，是我願意離開里拉。
She was so good to me. She was such a good woman.
她對我這麼好。她是這樣一個好女人。
And I was in love with her.
我愛上了她。
But once, on our way from Kanpur to Allahabad...
但有一次，從坎普爾阿拉哈巴德我們的方式......
little did I realise that like a boat in midstream...
沒想到，我認識到，像在中途船...
my life too was to be caught in cross currents.
我的生活也曾經是交叉電流被抓獲。
"Haul it, haul it, haul it."
“牽引它，它牽引，牽引它。”
"The boat is stuck in the middle of the ocean."
“船被卡在海洋中。”
"Be prudent, be prudent."
“要謹慎，要謹慎。”
"I can't think straight."
“我想不清楚。”
"The boat is stuck in the middle of the ocean."
“船被卡在海洋中。”
"Be prudent, be prudent."
“要謹慎，要謹慎。”
"Haul it, haul it, haul it."
“牽引它，它牽引，牽引它。”
"The clear open sky over the head."
“晴朗的廣闊天空的頭。”
"The clear open sky."
“清晰的天空開放”。
"Be prudent, boatman. There is storm in your boat."
“要謹慎，船夫，有暴風雨中你的船。”
"There is storm in your boat."
“有風暴在你的船。”
"The deep capricious waves."
“深反复無常的海浪。”
"Be prudent, be prudent."
“要謹慎，要謹慎。”
"The boat is stuck in the middle of the ocean."
“船被卡在海洋中。”
"Haul it, haul it, haul it."
“牽引它，它牽引，牽引它。”
"A piece of the glass floats away."
“一塊玻璃的浮了。”
"The iron too drowns."
“鐵太淹沒。”
"What are you thinking?"
“你在想什麼？”
"Be prudent, be prudent."
“要謹慎，要謹慎。”
"The boat is stuck in the middle of the ocean."
“船被卡在海洋中。”
"Haul it, haul it, haul it."
“牽引它，它牽引，牽引它。”
Aren't you feeling sleepy?
難道你不覺得困？
What are you thinking about? - Why do they sing "Beware"?
你在想什麼呢？ - 為什麼他們唱“小心”？
They say, these parts are dangerous. Jagga the bandit. He's from these parts.
他們說，這些部件是危險的。 Jagga土匪。他從這些部件。
Bandits? - Yes, but don't worry.
土匪？ - 是的，但不要擔心。
As of now, he must be fast asleep in some prison.
截至目前，他一定是在某些監獄快睡著了。
Go to bed. I'm feeling sleepy.
睡覺。我感覺昏昏欲睡。
In case you're afraid, I can come over. - No.
如果你害怕，我能過來。 - 號
Leela!
里拉！
No! The lady is with them!
沒有！這位女士是他們！
Leave me! Leave me! Leave me!
離開我！離開我！離開我！
You heartless bandits!
你無情土匪！
Where's your chief?
哪裡是你的頭兒？
What right have you to terrorise women from good families?
你有什麼權利從好家庭恐嚇女人？
Aren't you ashamed? - Ashamed?
難道你不感到羞恥？ - 羞愧？
Shame is for good folks, not for bandits and robbers.
羞恥是好鄉親，而不是土匪和強盜。
As for me, my grandfather was a bandit, my father was a bandit! But I wasn't.
至於我，我的祖父是一個土匪，我的父親是個強盜！但我不是。
And your husband went and made me one! - My husband?
和你的丈夫去了，讓我一個！ - 我的老公？
Who are you? - Jagga. And I was innocent.
你是誰？ -  Jagga。我是無辜的。
But without a shard of evidence, your husband framed me...
但是，如果沒有證據碎片，你的丈夫陷害我...
just because my father, my grandfather were bandits.
只是因為我的父親，我的祖父都是土匪。
He framed me for rape and he sent me to jail.
他誣陷我要強姦罪，他把我送到監獄。
So I've decided to prove your husband right.
所以，我決定權證明你的丈夫。
Coward!
懦夫！
See what's wrong with her.
看看她怎麼了。
Has she come to her senses?
有她來到她的感覺？
No, she's still in a swoon.
不，她仍處於昏厥。
Let her go, Chief. She's pregnant. She's going to become a mother.
讓她走，主任。她懷孕了。她會成為一個母親。
Touch her, and you go to hell.
觸摸她，你去地獄。
Pregnant? With a baby?
孕？帶寶寶？
Her husband said that children born of good folks turn out good.
她的丈夫說，天生好鄉親的孩子們練得不錯。
And children born of bandits...
和孩子出生的土匪...
turn out to be bandits. Always.
變成是土匪。總是。
Now let's see what the lawyer's son turns out to be.
現在讓我們看看律師的兒子變成什麼出來的人。
Send her back once she recovers.
送她回一旦她恢復。
Good are those born of good folks! And of bandits are bandits born.
好的是那些天生好鄉親！和強盜是土匪出身。
You should make me a gift. - What's the occasion?
你應該讓我的禮物。 - 什麼是機會？
Not any occasion. The lady is back.
沒有任何場合。這位女士又回來了。
What did you say? The lady?
你說什麼？這位女士？
Leela!
里拉！
Why is it dark in here?
為什麼是黑的嗎？
Nathu! Bansi! Naina!
乃堆！半絲！奈娜！
Lights! Tonight we celebrate!
燈！今晚我們慶祝！
Leela.
里拉。
It is you who lights up my life.
它是你誰照亮了我的生命。
Now that you're back, even the lights seem so bright!
既然你回來了，連燈光都顯得很亮！
Give me the wick.
給我燈芯。
But Leela, how did you escape? I hope you weren't in danger?
但是里拉，你是怎麼逃出來的？我希望你不會有危險？
Your love was with me. How could anyone even look up at me?
你的愛是我。怎麼會有人連抬頭看我？
You are tired. Change. I'll bring you your dressing gown.
你累了。更改。我給你帶你的晨衣。
These last four days.
這最後四天。
The last four days were like a lifetime.
最後四天就像一輩子。
I took the police and I looked everywhere for you.
我帶著警察和我到處找你。
All the while, I feared...
在這期間，我怕...
I feared you were in grave danger!
我怕你是處於嚴重危險之中！
But how did you escape? And who was this bandit?
可是你是怎麼逃出來的？那麼誰是這個強盜？
Some Jagga. He said that you had convicted him.
一些Jagga。他說，你有他定罪。
Jagga.
Jagga。
So he escaped to get even with me! If he has done anything to you...
於是，他逃到了報復我！如果他做了什麼嗎？
I'll see to it that he hangs! - At heart, he's a devil.
我會看到它，他掛起！ - 在心臟，他是個魔鬼。
But God saved me at the last moment. Thank God!
但上帝救了我在最後的時刻。謝天謝地！
Tell me something.
告訴我的東西。
Ask.
問。
Does a bandit's son necessarily become a bandit?
做了土匪的兒子必然成為一個強盜？
Yes, it's bound to happen.
是的，這是必然要發生的。
But why do you ask? - Just like that.
但你為什麼要問？ - 就這樣。
Let's see what comes first. Your becoming a magistrate, or...
讓我們來看看什麼是要先。你成為一個縣長，或...
Why? Is someone expected?
為什麼？是否有人預期？
A new guest.
新的客戶。
Now I don't have any chances of becoming a magistrate.
現在，我沒有成為一名裁判任何機會。
Why? What happened?
為什麼？發生了什麼？
Whatever... let's talk of something else.
無論...讓我們談點別的。
How do you like this?
你怎麼這樣呢？
Nice.
尼斯。
Listen... Are you annoyed with me?
聽著...你是惱火嗎？
Annoyed? No.
惱火？沒有。
Why should I be annoyed with you?
我為什麼要生氣呀？
Have my lunch sent over.
吃午飯送了過來。
What's the matter? Where are the servants?
怎麼了？在哪裡僕人？
God knows! Maybe they're all dead! I have to do all the chores.
天知道！也許他們都死了！我必須做的所有家務。
Let me help you. - You'd rather tell her all this.
我來幫你​​。 - 你寧願告訴她這一切。
She's sitting around like a queen!
她坐在那裡像一個女王！
Not to be cross with Leela. I told her not to strain herself.
不要與里拉交叉。我告訴她不要拉傷自己。
You know the condition she is in. And in a few days from now...
你知道這種情況她在，而且在幾天之內從現在開始......
She's going to bear the fruit of her sins!
她要承擔她的罪過的果實！
What are you saying?! - What everyone else is saying!
你在說什麼？！ - 所有人都在說！
For four days, she lived with a bandit! And Jagga that!
四天，她住了強盜！而Jagga的！
Don't you remember what he was convicted for?
難道你不記得他被定罪呢？
Do you enjoy making someone unhappy? The jaundiced eye sees all yellow.
你喜歡讓別人不高興呢？該偏見的眼光看所有的黃色。
Do you think you're beyond scrutiny? Don't you forget...
你覺得你以後的審查？難道你忘了？
women have had to stand the test of chastity. Because society asks for it.
婦女只好站在貞潔的考驗。因為社會需要它。
Bhabhi! (Sister-in-law)
Bhabhi！ （嫂子）
Forgive me Bhabhi, your pot is broken.
原諒我Bhabhi，你的鍋壞了。
It's only an earthen pot. But remember, a woman's honour is far more fragile.
這只是一個瓦盆。但要記住，女人的榮譽是更為脆弱。
Once disgraced, her honour can never be redeemed.
Once灰頭土臉，她的榮譽永遠不能被贖回。
Just answer my question!
只要回答我的問題！
Did you not know that your wife was seeing her lover on the sly?
你不知道你的妻子是看到偷偷地她的愛人？
The villagers used to say that. But I didn't heed what they said.
用村民們說。但我沒有理會他們說什麼。
You haven't yet told the court why your wife deserted you.
您還沒有在法庭上說，為什麼你的妻子拋棄了你。
You know it! Women are adulterous! - I know what that means!
你懂的！婦女通姦！ - 我知道這意味著什麼！
Raghu, how can you lose your cool in court?
Raghu，你怎麼能失去冷靜在法庭上？
I'm afraid your chances of magistrate ship may be clouded.
恐怕你縣長船的機會可能會蒙上陰影。
Chances of a magistrate ship? That's out of question now.
裁判官船上的機會？這是毫無疑問的了。
Can a lawyer whose wife is under suspicion ever become a magistrate?
律師受到懷疑，他的妻子是能永遠成為裁判官？
Raghu!
Raghu！
The whole town is agog! - What are you saying?
整個小鎮是急切！ - 你在說什麼？
Aren't you ashamed to talk like this about your wife?
難道你不羞於談論這樣你的妻子嗎？
I'm just saying what everyone is saying.
我只是說大家都在說。
Let them say what they want.
讓他們說他們想要什麼。
You're right. That's what I decided.
你是對的。這就是我的決定。
But how do I get rid of the suspicion? It's like a leech sucking on...
可是我怎麼擺脫猜疑？這就像一個水蛭吸上...
some dark corner of my mind! - What now?
我心中的一些陰暗的角落！ - 現在怎麼辦？
Nathu! Naina! Bhabhi!
乃堆！奈娜！ Bhabhi！
Where's everyone?
在哪裡大家？
Send Bhabhi over to me.
發送Bhabhi交給了我。
I am scared.
我害怕。
Why isn't someone coming to me?
為什麼沒有人來找我？
That's my husband. Please, send him over to me.
這是我的丈夫。請送他交給了我。
Look Raghu...
看看Raghu ...
I'm telling you again! That baby isn't going to be born in this house
我再告訴你！寶寶是不會在這個房子裡出生
If she wants to have her bastard, let her go elsewhere.
如果她想有她的混蛋，讓她去別的地方。
I'm not going to let the honour of my family be tainted.
我不會讓我的家族的榮譽被感染。
I'm going to throw this wanton woman out!
我要拋出此肆意的女人了！
No! I'm not going anywhere! No one can take me away from here!
沒有！我哪兒也不去！沒有人能帶我離開這裡！
He knows that I'm innocent! He trusts me, he trusts me!
他知道我是無辜的！他信任我，他信任我！
You're here! Now I'm afraid of no one!
你在這裡！現在恐怕沒有人！
Have you heard? They want to throw me out!
你聽說過嗎？他們想要把我扔出去！
They say I'm a wanton woman! They say, I've no right to be here!
他們說我是一個女人放肆！他們說，我已經沒有權利在這裡！
But now you're here. No one will dare anymore.
但是現在你在這裡。沒有人會再不敢。
Tell them I'm untainted! Tell them you trust me.
告訴他們我污點！告訴他們，你相信我。
Tell them I'm mothering your child.
告訴他們我省親你的孩子。
Have you fallen for what they say?
你愛上了他們說什麼？
You're the one who told me... I don't care for the barking dogs.
你是誰告訴我......我不關心狂吠的狗之一。
If you desert me, who else in this world can I turn to?
如果你拋棄我，在這個世界上還有誰我能找誰？
Tell me... tell me that you trust me!
告訴我......告訴我，你相信我！
Do you think you're above scrutiny?
你以為你是上面的審查？
Don't you forget women have had to stand the test of chastity.
難道你忘了女人不得不站在貞潔的考驗。
Why are you quiet? Speak... speak!
你為什麼要安靜？說...說話！
You can see the state I'm in. I'm afraid... afraid!
你可以看到我在狀態。我怕...怕！
I'm going to become a mother ...the mother of your child.
我要成為一個母親......你的孩子的母親。
Have mercy! This is your baby. This baby is yours!
憐憫！這是你的寶寶。這個嬰兒是你的！
Get out! Get out of here!
出去！離開這裡！
"A dutiful wife like Sita."
“孝順的妻子像寺塔”。
"You gave exile to her."
“你給流放她。”
"Why didn't the earth rip apart?"
“為什麼大地不裂開？”
"Why didn't the sky rip apart?"
“為什麼天空不撕開？”
"Women have to endure injustice."
“婦女不得不忍受不公平。”
"The dear one of Lord Ram."
“親愛的, 拉姆主(Lord Rama)。”
"Look, the King of the palace."
“你看，宮殿裡的國王。”
"What a game is he playing!"
“他在玩什麼遊戲！”
"From the shell, a pearl, and in the muck."
“從貝，珍珠，並渣土。”
"The beautiful lotus is blossoming."
“美麗的荷花正在開花。”
"Lord, Your ways are strange."
“(Lord Rama)拉姆主啊，你的道路很奇怪。”
"Congratulations, Lawyer! A son has born to you."
“恭喜你，律師！一個兒子出生給你。”
Son of a decent family! Born in a filthy gutter!
一個體面的家庭的兒子！出生在一個骯髒的排水溝！
"Lord, Your ways are strange."
“(Lord Rama)拉姆主啊，你的道路很奇怪。”
Do you not know what your wife and your son went through...
你不知道你的妻子和你的兒子經歷了...
after you shut your doors on them? - No
之後你關閉你的門上呢？ - 無
Nor did you try to find out.
你也沒有嘗試找出。
But I can tell you.
但我可以告訴你。
To get out of your way, your wife left Lucknow.
為了擺脫自己的方式，你的妻子離開了勒克瑙。
And your innocent son grew up in a Bombay slum.
而你的天真無邪的兒子在孟買貧民窟長大。
One day...
一天...
Police! Scram!
警察！急停！
Greetings, sir.
問候，先生。
Hey Nathu... - Hello, Constable.
哎...乃堆 - 你好，警員。
What are you up there like a monkey? Why don't you go to school?
你是什​​麼人在那裡像一隻猴子？你為什麼不上學？
At school, the master asks for fees.
在學校裡，主要求的費用。
My father hasn't the money to send me to school.
我父親有沒有錢送我去上學。
Look at Leela's son, Raj. He lives in this slum too.
看看里拉的兒子，拉吉。他住在貧民窟這太。
His mother is worse off. Yet she sends her boy to such a big school.
他的母親是更糟。然而，她送她的孩子到這樣一所大學校。
What did you say? He isn't a boy. He's a sissy!
你說什麼？他不是一個男孩。他是一個娘娘腔！
Ma, why do you put oil in my hair? - Oil keeps the hair soft.
媽，你為什麼放油，在我的頭髮？ - 油保持頭髮柔軟。
But why do boys in the neighbourhood call me sissy?
但是為什麼男孩在附近叫我娘娘腔？
So what? How do they compare with you?
所以呢？他們怎麼跟你比？
You're a good boy who goes to school.
你是個好孩子誰去上學。
You'll grow up to become an educated man.
你長大後成為一個有教養的人。
And those vagabonds will go to jail.
而那些流浪者將坐牢。
Mother, who are called vagabonds?
母親，誰被稱為流浪者？
The ones who just tramp around.
那些誰只是流浪漢身邊。
Those who think that whatever belongs to others, belongs to them.
那些誰認為，無論屬於別人的，屬於他們。
Those who gamble and drink instead of going to school.
這些誰賭博，喝酒，而不是去上學。
And they have fun!
他們有樂趣！
Ma, when I grow up, I'll become vagabond too.
馬，當我長大了，我會成為流浪漢了。
Nonsense! You'll become a lawyer.
廢話！你會成為一名律師。
Then a magistrate.
然後裁判官。
And then, a judge.
然後，法官。
Raj!
拉吉！
You're sitting here? Everyone's out there buying chocolates.
你坐在這裡？每個人都在那裡買巧克力。
I don't have money
我沒有錢
Why, doesn't your mother give you money?
為什麼，沒有你媽給你錢？
Daddy gives me a whole Rupee every day!
爸爸每天都讓我整個盧比！
You're rich. And I'm poor.
你很富有。而且我窮。
Eat this - No.
吃這個 - 號
Ma says never ask for anything to eat.
馬雲說從來沒有要求任何東西吃。
If she told you not to ask, go ahead and snatch it.
如果她叫你別問，繼續搶奪。
Wild!
野生！
Wild? - No, no, no.
野生？ - 不不不。
You're coming to my place this evening, aren't you?
你今天晚上來我家，不是嗎？
Why, what's happening? - My birthday party!
為什麼，發生了什麼？ - 我的生日派對！
You must come! It's going to be fun!
你一定要來！這將是有趣！
You know, Daddy has ordered such a huge cake!
要知道，爸爸已下令如此巨大的蛋糕！
Happy birthday to you!
祝你生日快樂！
Thank you, thank you, thank you!
謝謝你，謝謝你，謝謝你！
Let's go and eat ice cream.
讓我們去和吃冰淇淋。
Raj, aren't you giving me a gift?
拉吉，你不給我一個禮物嗎？
I didn't have money to buy anything. I'll give you some other time.
我沒有錢購買任何東西。我給你一些其他的時間。
Must you only buy something to make a gift?
你一定要只買東西，使一個禮物嗎？
You can give me a flower. - Really?
你可以給我一朵花。 - 真的嗎？
Here you are.
這個給你。
Someday, I'm going to make lots of money.
有一天，我會賺很多錢。
And I'll buy a gift for you. Something better than all this.
我會買禮物給你。東西比這個要好。
Do that.
去做。
But can anything be better than this flower?
但還有比這更好的花？
Ritu! Ritu! Your father is calling you! - Coming!
日圖！日圖！你爸爸喊你！ - 來了！
Come on Raj, meet my father.
來吧拉吉，迎接我的父親。
You always say this.
你總是說這一點。
Ritu, say hello to the Judge"
瑞圖萬方，問好法官“
Hello, Judge.
你好，法官。
Bless you.
祝福你。
You've grown up in these four years You must've forgotten me.
你在這四年你一定是忘了我長大了。
Happy birthday
生日快樂
I've just arrived from Lucknow. I owe you a present.
我剛剛從勒克瑙到達。我欠你一個禮物。
As of now, I can give you a flower.
截至目前，我可以給你一朵花。
Here you are.
這個給你。
Let me put it on your hair.
讓我把它放在你的頭髮。
Someone has already put a flower over there.
有人已經把花那邊。
Raj has given me this flower
拉吉給了我這種花
Daddy, this is Raj. He's in my class.
爸爸，這是拉吉。他是在我的課。
I see. - Hello.
我懂了。 - 你好。
Hello.
你好。 - 你好。
God bless you, son"
上帝保佑你，兒子“
Raj says that he will become a judge when he grows up.
拉吉說，當他長大後，他將成為一名法官。
Very good!
很好！
Your father must be a real gentleman.
你父親必須是一個真正的紳士。
What does your father do?
你爸爸是做什麼？
I don't have my father. I have only my mother
我沒有我的父親。我只有我的母親
Has he passed away? - No! Don't say that!
他已經過世了？ - 不！不要說！
My mother says he is alive. But...
我的母親說，他還活著。但...
He doesn't live with you ...and you haven't seen him either?
他不和你住在一起...你沒見過他要么？
Your father is a strange man. - Not a word about my father.
你爸爸是一個奇怪的人。 - 不是關於我父親一句話。
Else... else...
否則......否則......
Raj! - Rita!
拉吉！ - 麗塔！
How can you let your daughter play with boys like him?
你怎麼可以讓你的女兒與男生喜歡他玩？
Go to play, Ritu"
去打球，瑞圖萬方“
Why, what's wrong with the boy? I like him.
為什麼，有什麼不對的男孩嗎？我喜歡他。
He doesn't even know his father's name, and you like him?
他甚至不知道他父親的名字，你喜歡他嗎？
I'd say he's just a wastrel - Forget it.
我會說他是個敗家子 - 算了吧。
Must you hang on to those rotten old ideas?
你必須掛在那些腐朽的舊觀念？
What was the Bandit's name?
什麼是土匪的名字嗎？
Yes, Jagga.
是的，Jagga。
I remember you saying the same at his trial.
我記得你在他的試驗說同樣的。
That a bandit's son always becomes a bandit.
一個土匪的兒子總是變成了土匪。
I still stand by that principle.
我還是堅持這一原則立場。
Principles, principles and principles! It's because of these blind dogmas...
原則，方針和原則！這是因為這些盲目的教條...
that you lost someone as precious as Leela.
你失去了一個為珍貴里拉。
And because of your principles, you never married again.
而且因為你的原則，你永遠不會再結婚。
The dry parched desert that your life is, is your own doing.
乾燥炎熱的沙漠中你的生活，是你自己做的。
So much so that you would rather destroy a friendship...
正因如此，你寧願毀了友誼......
between two innocent children? Why, what has the poor child done...
兩名無辜的孩子之間？為什麼，是什麼可憐的孩子做...
to bring you to harm?
給你帶來傷害？
Not this boy. But it was...
不是這個男孩。但它是...
someone like him who destroyed my life ...and brought me to disgrace.
有人喜歡他誰破壞了我的生活......而給我帶來了恥辱。
Maybe today, he too says what this boy just said...
也許在今天，他也說什麼這孩子剛才說的...
I'm only my mother's son ...I have no father.
我只是我母親的兒子......我沒有父親。
In every urchin I see him...
在每一個頑童我看見他...
the one whom my wife bore, the one who isn't mine.
在其中一人我的妻子孔，誰是不是我的。
My wife's, yet not mine.
我的妻子的，但不是我的。
Rita looks good in that photo, doesn't she?
麗塔看起來不錯，在這照片，不是嗎？
But Ma, why do you work so hard? This is why you fall ill.
但馬雲，你為什麼要這麼辛苦？這就是為什麼你生病。
I'm not going to let you work anymore, you understand?
我不會讓你工作了，你明白嗎？
You mad boy! If I don't work, how are we going to eat?
你瘋了的孩子！如果我不工作，我們怎麼吃？
I'm a man. I'm the one who is going to work.
我是男人。我是誰去上班的人。
From tomorrow, no going to school!
從明天起，不上學！
You won't go to school? Won't you?
你會不會去上學？不會吧？
How will you become a gentleman, unless you educate yourself?
你將如何成為一個紳士，除非你教育自己？
You want to be a vagabond! - Mother!
你想成為一個流浪漢！ - 母親！
Without schooling, how can you become a lawyer, a magistrate, a judge?
如果沒有教育，你怎麼能成為一名律師，裁判官，法官？
If you say so, I'll go to school ...and I'll work too.
如果你這麼說，我會去上學......我就工作了。
But I won't become a judge. At Rita's I met a judge.
但我不會成為一名法官。在麗塔的我遇見了一名法官。
I didn't like him.
我不喜歡他。
"Go for a stroll, those who are going."
“去散步，那些誰去了。”
"Since when we have been waiting,
“從什麼時候開始，我們一直在等待，
we cobblers."
我們鞋匠“。
Page 120.
第120頁。
Raj.
拉吉。
Good morning, teacher. Sorry, I'm late.
老師早上好。不好意思我遲到了。
I work, you know. I work - What's all this?
我的工作，你知道。我的工作 - 這是什麼呢？
Brush, wax... I give you a good polish.
刷機，蠟...我給你一個很好的拋光。
Your name has been struck from the rolls.
你的名字已經從輥襲擊。
What? - You can't study here anymore.
什麼？ - 你不能再在這裡學習。
But I've brought the fees too! If you say so, I'll stop polishing boots.
但我帶來的費用呢！如果你這麼說，我會停下來拋光靴。
Silence!
安靜！
So I can't study here any longer, can I?
所以，我不能再在這裡學習，可以嗎？
No.
沒有。
For a minute, can I talk to Rita? I have a gift for her.
一分鐘，我可以跟麗塔？我對她的禮物。
Rita's father has transferred her out of this school. They have moved.
麗塔的父親把她走出這所學校。他們感動。
Why did you kick my ball?
你為什麼踢我的球？
Forgive me, I stepped on it by mistake.
原諒我，我錯踩在上面。
How dare a boot-polish-boy? - Hit him!
怎麼敢引導拋光男孩？ - 打他！
Beat him! Beat him!
打他！打他！
You're just a boot-polish boy. You dare take me on?
你只是一個引導的波蘭男孩。你敢帶我？
Hit him!
打他！
His coat... strip him!
他的上衣......剝奪了他！
Beat him! Beat him!
打他！打他！
My Ma is ill. Let me go to my Ma.
我媽病了。讓我去我媽。
You can hit me some other time. My Ma is ill. Let me go to my Ma.
你可以打我一些其他的時間。我媽病了。讓我去我媽。
Your Ma is ill? - Yes
你媽病了？ - 是的
His Ma is ill!
他媽病了！
Run! Uncle Jagga is here! Run!
跑！ Jagga叔叔就在這裡！跑！
Get up. Come with me.
起來。跟我來。
Where to? - Wherever I go.
去哪兒？ - 無論我去哪裡。
From now on, you go wherever I go.
從現在起，你去的地方我去。
That's what your father wanted.
這是你的父親想要的東西。
You know my father? - Yes.
你知道我的父親？ - 是的。
I knew him.
我認識他。
Whatever I am today, is all thanks to him.
今天不管我是誰，都要感謝他。
I owe your Dad an old debt.
我欠你爸爸的舊債。
Then you'll surely help me find a job somewhere?
然後，你一定會幫我的地方，找工作？
Job? What job? - Whatever! I'll do anything!
工作？什麼工作？ - 隨你！我會做任何事情！
My Ma is sick! We haven't anything to eat! Give me any job!
我媽病了！我們沒有東西吃！給我任何工作！
I'll clean the dishes, sweep floors, carry luggage... I'll do anything!
我得先清洗餐具，打掃地面，搬運行李......我會做任何事情！
Just give me a job! Give me a job!
只要給我一份工作！給我一份工作！
You fool! Only fools work.
你個笨蛋！只有傻瓜才會工作。
You're a smart boy. And you talk of working?
你是個聰明的孩子。和你說話的工作？
Unless I work, how will I eat? How will I feed my mother?
除非我的工作，我將如何吃？我怎麼養活我的媽媽？
Steal - Steal?
偷 - 偷？
Stealing... no!
偷......不！
Yes, yes, yes! Steal! Steal! Steal!
對對對！偷！偷！偷！
Pick pockets, locks, rob, kill.
挑選口袋，鎖，搶劫，殺人。
Raj!
拉吉！
You took so long, son.
你花了這麼長時間，孩子。
You've been hungry all day. Go on, eat food.
你已經餓了一整天。去，吃的食物。
Food? Have you cooked? - Yes, why not?
食品？你做的？ - 是的，為什麼不？
It's over there, under the plate.
在那邊，下盤。
The bread is warm. I even cooked potatoes.
麵包是溫暖的。我甚至煮熟的土豆。
Take some. It's on the shelf.
拿一些。這是在貨架上。
Have you found it?
你有沒有發現呢？
Yes Ma, I found it.
是馬，我發現它。
The bread, and potatoes too.
麵包和馬鈴薯了。
The potatoes are delicious.
土豆好吃。
Eat it then. Give me a bread too. I'm very hungry.
吃它呢。給我一個麵包了。我好餓。
Very hungry. - Bread?
餓極了。 - 麵包？
Yes, Ma. I'll get it right now.
是的，馬。我會得到它現在。
Right now.
馬上。
Yes, yes, yes! Steal! Steal! Steal!
對對對！偷！偷！偷！
Pick pockets, locks, rob, kill.
挑選口袋，鎖，搶劫，殺人。
You thief!
你的賊！
Stealing bread? - Excuse me, my Ma is hungry.
偷麵包嗎？ - 對不起，我的馬是餓了。
She hasn't had anything to eat in three days
她什麼都沒三天吃
Son of a gun! Off you go to the cops!
中槍的兒子！關你去報警！
What's your name? I asked you what's your name?
你叫什麼名字？我問你你叫什麼名字？
Raj!
拉吉！
Father's name?
父親的名字？
Ma has never told me my father's name.
馬雲從來沒有告訴我，我父親的名字。
Where does your mother live? I asked you where your mother lives.
你媽媽在哪裡住？我問你你的母親住在哪裡。
I won't tell you. I won't.
我不會告訴你。我不會。
If you don't, who pays for your bail? You'll go to jail. You know that?
如果不這樣做，誰支付的保釋金？你會去坐牢。你懂的？
Jail!
監獄！
Where are you running? - Don't send me to jail!
你在哪裡運行？ - 不要送我去坐牢！
My Ma is hungry. Don't send me to jail!
我的馬是餓了。不要送我去坐牢！
Afraid, son? Don't be. This is just your first step.
怕兒子？不要。這僅僅是第一步。
The road ahead is very long.
前面的路很長。
Hey, are you mad?
嘿，你瘋了嗎？
Why are you laughing at your bread?
為什麼你笑你的麵包嗎？
This bread...
這麵包...
you know this bread? She makes you dance.
你知道這個麵包嗎？她讓你跳舞。
What do you mean? - She made me dance!
你什麼意思？ - 她讓我跳舞！
Outside the jail twelve years ago, had I found her...
監獄十二年前外面，有我找到了她......
would I be here time and again, for her sake?
我會在這裡一次又一次地為她著想？
You've had enough for free. Come on, the jailer is calling you.
你已經有足夠的自由。來吧，獄卒叫你。
Your time's up. Find yourself some other hotel.
你的時間到了。發現自己的一些其他的酒店。
Time is over? - Yes.
時間到？ - 是的。
Okay, boss! I don't like the food of this place!
好了，老大！我不喜歡這個地方的食物！
Now I will eat in Taj Mahal Hotel.
現在，我會吃在泰姬陵酒店。
If you want to eat at the Taj Mahal Hotel, stop thieving.
如果你想在泰姬瑪哈酒店吃飯，停止偷竊。
Yes, boss. - Stop picking pockets.
是的，老闆。 - 停止採摘口袋。
- And do some honest work.
是的，老闆。 - 做一些誠實的工作。
Sure. I'm going on a pilgrimage.
當然。我要去朝聖。
"I am a vagabond. I am a vagabond."
“我是流浪者，我是流浪者。”
"In troubled times, I am the star in the sky."
“亂世中，我是天上的星星。”
"I am a vagabond."
“我是流浪者。”
"I don't have a house or a family."
“我沒有房子或一個家庭。”
"Nobody loves me. Nobody loves me."
“沒有人愛我。沒人喜歡我。”
"There is no promise of meeting someone from across."
“沒有來自各地的約會和諾言。”
"I'm the beloved of isolated and alien places."
“我被孤獨和外來的地方所愛。”
"I am a vagabond. I am a vagabond."
“我是流浪者，我是流浪者。”
"In troubled times, I am the star in the sky."
“亂世中，我是天上的星星。”
"I am a vagabond."
“我是流浪者。”
"I'm not flourishing, I am not ruined."
“我不兴旺，我也不消亡。”
"Still I sing happy songs."
“不過我唱歡歌”。
"My heart is filled with wounds."
“我的心充滿了傷口。”
"But still these lively eyes smile."
“但是，我的眼睛仍然有活潑的微笑。”
"World.."
“世界..啊...”
"World, I am troubled by your sorrows or misfortunes."
“世界，我被你的悲傷和不幸所困擾。”
"I am a vagabond. I am a vagabond."
“我是流浪者，我是流浪者。”
"In troubled times, I am the star in the sky."
“亂世中，我是天上的星星。”
"I am a vagabond."
“我是流浪者。”
Hands up!
舉手！
Raj! Raj!
拉吉！拉吉！
Raj! You had me scared.
拉吉！你讓我害怕。
Come on, give me a hug.
來吧，給我一個擁抱。
Well boss, how is business?
好老闆，生意如何？
Hey, are you talking English? - This time in jail...
嘿，你說英語嗎？ - 這一次在監獄裡......
I came across one of the politicos. I thought I'd make the most of it.
我碰到的政客之一。我想我會充分利用它。
I could use it.
我可以使用它。
Tell me, what news of Ma? You told her, didn't you?
告訴我，馬的什麼消息？你告訴她，不是嗎？
Yes, a long time ago. She thinks you're away on a long business trip...
是的，在很久以前。她認為你離開上長期出差...
with your boss. When you go home, you must go home in style.
與你的老闆。當你回家，你必須在風格回家。
I have it all fixed. - First, tell me...
我把它所有的固定。 - 首先，告訴我...
have you been sending money to Ma? - Of course! On the 1st of every month!
你一直寄錢給馬？ - 當然！在每月的1日！
Say, you'd need some money, wouldn't you? Keep this.
再說了，你需要一些錢，不是嗎？保持這個。
Looking for this thing?
尋找這件事情？
I guessed it was for me. So why not take it for myself?
我猜這是對我來說。那麼，為什麼不把它為我自己？
Want a ten or a twenty? No?
希望十年或二十？沒有？
Bravo, my boy! You'll make your guru proud someday.
布拉沃，我的孩子！你會讓你的驕傲大師有一天。
And someday, I'll ask your father what the gentleman's son grows up to be.
有一天，我會問你爸爸是什麼紳士的兒子長大後成為。
Mother!
母親！
Hello, mummy darling! Hello! - Raj! Raj!
你好，親愛的媽媽！你好！ - 拉吉！拉吉！
Raj, I've been dying to see you! This time, it has been a whole year!
拉吉，我一直想見到你！這一次，它已經整整一年！
Where has this boss of yours been taking you to?
哪裡有這樣的老闆你的被帶你到？
This time, I've been to London and more.
這一次，我去過倫敦和更多。
London?
倫敦？
London, France, Paris, New York, America.
倫敦，法國，巴黎，紐約，美國。
On my way back, I even stopped at Arthur Road.
在回來的路上，我甚至停在亞瑟路。
My boss is into import and export. - What's that?
我的老闆是到進口和出口。 - 那是什麼？
You don't know import-export? You're so naive.
你不知道的進出口？你這麼天真。
Your son is about to become a big businessman, and you don't know...
你兒子即將成為一個大的商人，你不知道...
what import-export is? Listen to this, Ma.
什麼進出口是什麼？聽此，馬。
Import-export means moving the money between here and there.
進出口意味著將在這裡和那裡的錢。
But mostly, it comes in this way.
但大多數情況下，它有這種方式。
How would I know? You've even started talking English.
我怎麼會知道？你甚至已經開始談論英語。
Sit, I'll get tea for you.
坐，我去拿茶給你。
What are you looking at?
你在看什麼？
I'm a thief.
我是一個小偷。
A lying thief.
一個躺在小偷。
I've sinned.
我犯了罪。
Why did you turn that photo over?
你為什麼把那張照片了嗎？
Whenever I look at it...
每當我看它...
she seems to be staring at me.
她似乎在我盯著。
She brings back childhood memories. Why don't you admit that?
她帶回童年的回憶。你為什麼不承認？
Where could she be now? Why don't you try to locate her?
她會在哪裡，現在呢？你為什麼不嘗試找到她嗎？
Childhood days, and childhood friends ...do they ever come back, Ma?
童年，童年的朋友......你他們曾經回來，媽？
I'm going out. - But your tea?
我要出去。 - 但是，你的茶？
Forget it. I've got to see a friend.
算了吧。我得去看一個朋友。
My son he is! Silly boy!
我的兒子就是他！傻孩子！
"1, 2, 3. Come, the weather is lovely."
“1，2，3，來吧，天氣是可愛的。”
"Come. 1, 2, 3. Come, the weather is lovely."
“來吧，1，2，3，來吧，天氣是可愛的。”
"Meeting covertly at night is considered as sin by others."
“在晚上偷偷摸摸會議被認為是他人的罪。”
"Sin."
“罪。”
"1, 2, 3. Come, the weather is lovely."
“1，2，3，來吧，天氣是可愛的。”
"Come. 1, 2, 3. Come, the weather is lovely."
“來吧，1，2，3，來吧，天氣是可愛的。”
"This is salacious youth."
“這是色情的青春。”
"It is crazy for you."
“這是為你瘋狂。”
"1, 2, 3. Come, the weather is lovely."
“1，2，3，來吧，天氣是可愛的。”
"Come. 1, 2, 3. Come, the weather is lovely."
“來吧，1，2，3，來吧，天氣是可愛的。”
"Why do you reject me?"
“你為什麼要拒絕我？”
"Why don't you look in my eyes?"
“你為什麼不看著我的眼睛？”
"Rob, the world is yours."
“羅布說，世界是你們的。”
"Why are you afraid of love?"
“你為什麼害怕愛？”
"1, 2, 3. Come, the weather is lovely."
“1，2，3，來吧，天氣是可愛的。”
"Come. 1, 2, 3. Come, the weather is lovely."
“來吧，1，2，3，來吧，天氣是可愛的。”
How much did you make today? - Ten thousand five hundred.
你今天賺多少了什麼？ - 一萬零五百名。
Fifty-Fifty.
百分之五十。
Why only fifty-fifty? You can have many times more.
為什麼只有百分之五十？你可以有很多次。
How? - Tomorrow morning...
怎麼樣？ - 明天早上...
a bank is being inaugurated. Say, how's the opportunity?
銀行正在揭牌。我說，怎麼樣的機會呢？
A sleight of hand, and there's a hundred thousand or so going.
變戲法，而且有十萬左右去。
All you need is a car. - Car?
所有你需要的是汽車。 - 汽車？
A good car. - For me, that's a sleight of hand.
一輛好車​​。 - 對我來說，這是變戲法。
Eleven tomorrow. - Where? - I'll tell you where.
十一明天。 - 在哪裡？ - 我會告訴你在哪裡。
Okay, boss.
好了，老闆。
Good! Someday, you'll surely make me proud.
好！有一天，你一定會令我感到驕傲。
It's late.
晚了。
You have to make it by eleven.
你必須一一做到。
First class car!
一等車！
Car? Where? - Out there
汽車？哪裡？ - 在外面
Who's driving it? - No idea.
誰在駕駛呢？ - 不知道。
A girl just got down and walked into that shop.
一個女孩剛剛下來，走進了商店。
Keys? - With her, maybe.
鑰匙？ - 有了她，也許。
That one? - Yes.
那個？ - 是的。
Idiot! Can't you see?
白痴！難道你不知道？
Found it?
找到了？
No keys here. - Then?
這裡沒有鑰匙。 - 然後？
Return the bag. - What for?
返回囊中。 - 做什麼的？
It will make things easier. We'll make it work.
這將使事情變得更容易。我們將使它發揮作用。
How will you return it?
你將如何恢復呢？
What happened? - I've been robbed!
發生了什麼？ - 我被搶了！
Who did it? - I didn't notice.
誰幹的？ - 我沒有注意到。
He was with you!
他和你在一起！
I had it a moment ago - You didn't notice who robbed you?
我有它剛才 - 你沒注意到誰搶你嗎？
Had I noticed, I would've caught him!
假如我注意到，我會抓到他！
You...
您...
Yes you! - Who me?
是的，就是你！ - 我是誰？
Look, there goes the thief! Stop! Thief!
你看，那還有小偷！停止！賊！
He jumped over the wall!
他翻過圍牆！
Wait here
在這兒等著
Come on, help me.
來吧，幫助我。
There you are! Hiding!
你在這！隱藏！
Aren't you ashamed? Give it to me. Else, I'll beat you to pulp.
難道你不感到羞恥？把它給我。否則，我會打敗你的紙漿。
I'm going to kill you! Give me!
我要殺了你！給我嗎！
Where are you running away?
你在哪裡逃跑？
Give the purse!
給錢包！
You dare stare at me like that?
你敢盯著我這樣？
Hey... knife!
哎...刀！
Are you running away? Coward!
你是離家出走？懦夫！
Coward!
懦夫！
Scoundrel!
惡棍！
He ran away
他跑了
Anyway, here's your purse"
總之，這裡是你的錢包“
Keep it.
收下。
You've been through so much trouble for my sake.
你已經經歷為我著想這麼多麻煩。
No trouble. I've taken more.
沒事。我已經採取了更多。
I should apologise. You risked your life to get my purse back.
我應該道歉。你冒著你的生活，讓我的錢包了。
And I suspected you. - Not your fault.
我懷疑你。 - 不是你的錯。
It's just my looks.
這只是我的外表。
Sometimes even the police are mistaken.
有時候連警察都錯了。
Bye
再見
How was the show? - No use.
怎麼樣的節目？ - 沒有用。
We'll find a car. Why worry? Get over to the place.
我們會找到了一輛車。為什麼要擔心？獲得到的地方。
I'll join you after a change of clothes.
換洗的衣服後，我會加入你。
Hey Romeo! You tear your clothes no sooner than you see a girl!
嘿羅密歐！你壞你的衣服不早於你看到一個女孩！
Get lost. - Get going.
走開。 - 走了。
Stop! Thief!
停止！賊！
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡？
Inside.
內。
Inside? What do you want? - Strange question.
內？你想要什麼？ - 奇怪的問題。
Your boss is the one who called me. And you ask me what I want?
你的老闆是誰罵我的人。你問我想要什麼？
The boss, or the lady? Who called you?
老闆，還是女士？誰給你打電話？
Yes, the lady.
是的，夫人。
So you're the one who fixes the piano?
所以，你是誰修復了鋼琴的人嗎？
Yes! The piano fixer!
是!鋼琴定影液！
Is the piano in there? - Are pianos kept outside?
是有鋼琴嗎？ - 是否保持鋼琴之外？
No! Inside. Come on in, else I'll get into trouble.
沒有！內。來吧，不然我會惹上麻煩。
Looks like a billionaire's palace!
看起來像一個億萬富翁的宮殿！
Hello, darling. - What did you say?
你好，親愛的。 - 你說什麼？
The mantle!
地幔！
What a lovely mantle!
多麼可愛的披風！
What a grand mansion!
什麼盛大豪宅！
The mantle!
地幔！
What kind of a joke is this? Here's the piano.
什麼樣的笑話，這是？這裡的鋼琴。
This piano is in bad shape. Badly damaged.
這架鋼琴是在惡劣的形狀。嚴重受損。
Look.
看。
Rotten! It'll take me time to fix it. Go on, get back to work.
爛！它會帶我的時間來修復它。去吧，回去工作。
I'll fix it.
我會解決它。
Who's playing my piano?
誰在玩我的鋼琴？
You? - You!
您？ - 你！
I'm mistaken, once again I thought it must be a thief.
我錯了，我再次想這一定是小偷。
That's what I am. - What?
那我是什麼。 - 什麼？
I mean, who else but a thief would come in uninvited?
我的意思是，人誰而是一個小偷進來不請自來？
No, it's good of you to have come.
不，這是很好的你來了。
You did me a favour. I should've called you over.
你幫了我的忙。我應該叫你過來。
But I didn't know your address. How did you find out my address?
但我不知道你的地址。你是怎麼找到我的地址？
What? - How did you find out my address?
什麼？ - 你是怎麼找到我的地址？
No, don't ask me that. It's a secret.
不，不要問我。這是個秘密。
Let's say, it's luck that has led me to your doorstep.
比方說，它的運氣已經使我您的家門口。
Please be seated - Thanks.
請坐 - 謝謝。
Cigarette?
香煙？
Lighter?
打火機？
No, thanks. Matches.
不用了，謝謝。火柴。
Madam, he's the piano-fixer... - Piano fixer?
女士，他是鋼琴固定器...  - 鋼琴定影液？
Your servant thinks I'm here to fix the piano.
你的僕人認為我到這裡來修復鋼琴。
But you said... - Never mind, take the call. Go on.
但是你說...  - 沒關係，接電話。繼續。
Strange fellow. He took you for a piano mechanic.
奇怪的傢伙。他把你的鋼琴技工。
Not his fault. It's just my looks.
不是他的錯。這只是我的外表。
Inspector sahib, no thief came in here.
督察老爺，沒有小偷來到這裡。
Please wait here.
請在這裡等候。
Inspector?
督察？
What brings the police here? Excuse me, I'll be back.
什麼風吹警察嗎？對不起，我會回來的。
A car thief has sneaked into one of the houses in this neighbourhood.
偷車賊已經潛入在這附近的房屋之一。
Have you seen anyone? - No, no one came in here.
你見過的人？ - 沒有，沒有一個人來到這裡。
She's wrong about no one coming in here.
她是錯的沒有一個人來這裡。
I happen to be a visitor. Would you be looking for me?
我碰巧是一個客人。你會找我嗎？
No... how could this be?
不......這怎麼可能？
Okay. Forgive me.
好的。原諒我。
Come.
來。
Grand house. - Yes. It belongs to the Judge.
大房子。 - 是的。它屬於法官。
Judge? - Yes, he's my guardian.
法官？ - 是的，他是我的監護人。
Guardian?
監護人？
Like the guard on the train ...signalling red and green?
像火車上的衛兵......信令紅色和綠色的嗎？
No. After my father passed away, I have been his ward.
號我的父親去世後，我一直在他的病房。
For the sake of my education, he left Lucknow and he came to Bombay.
對於我的教育著想，他離開勒克瑙，他來到孟買。
I am much obliged to him.
我非常感謝他。
Do judges sport such grand houses? He must be making a pile on the side.
不要法官體育運動盛大這樣的房子？他必須做在旁邊一堆。
What a thing to say! The judge is very principled.
什麼事要說！法官是非常有原則。
He never spares criminals. - I hope God spares him!
他從不吝惜罪犯。 - 我希望上帝饒恕他！
Not to worry. If you're ever arraigned in his court, let me defend your case.
不用擔心。如果你曾經在他的法院過堂，讓我捍衛你的情況。
You... lawyer? - Yes.
你......律師？ - 是的。
I took you for a schoolgirl.
我把你的女學生。
That was a nice one. A couple of months, and I'll be an advocate.
這是一個好一個。幾個月了，我會的倡導者。
Would you like to see my degree?
你想看到我的學位？
A judge lives here. And a lawyer too. Leaves only one to make a full court!
法官住在這裡。和一名律師了。只剩一個使一個完整的法庭！
Yours truly. And here I am. - And what are you up to?
敬上。而我在這裡。 - 你在忙什麼？
I steal.
我偷。
Stealing, picking pockets, locks, ladies' purses, like yours...
偷竊，採摘的口袋，鎖具，女士皮包，像你...
that's what I'm up to. - You're joking again. Be seated.
這就是我到。 - 你又在開玩笑。就座。
You don't think I'm a thief? - No, I think you're a gentleman.
你不覺得我是小偷？ - 不，我認為你是一個紳士。
This is the new world order!
這是新的世界秩序！
The thieves, the hoodwinkers, they all dress in first class suits like...
盜賊的hoodwinkers，他們都穿著一流的西裝像...
...I'm wearing and we take them for gentlemen.
...我穿的，我們把他們的紳士。
But those who work hard for an honest living and dress shabbily...
但是，這些誰很難誠實的生活工作和打扮寒酸...
...are labelled tramps and wastrels. The capitalists, the blackmarketeers...
...標記流浪漢和wastrels。資本家的blackmarketeers ...
the profiteers, the usurers... who are they? Thieves, like I am!
奸商，高利貸者......他們是誰？盜賊，像我！
You sound like a stock broker or a banker.
你聽起來像一個股票經紀人或銀行家。
You might say that give and take of money is what I'm concerned with.
你可能會說，給予和索取金錢是什麼，我很擔心。
As far as banks are concerned, I visit banks regularly.
至於銀行方面，我經常訪問銀行。
Be seated.
就座。
Tell me your name.
告訴我你的名字。
Tell me, whose photo is this? - Mine.
告訴我，他的照片是這樣嗎？ - 我的。
You? - Yes, when I was young.
您？ - 是的，當我還年輕。
It's a birthday photo.
這是一個生日照片。
Your name? - Rita. Why?
你的名字？ - 麗塔。為什麼？
Ms Rita, would you like to come to my house?
麗塔女士，你願意來我家？
I'd like to show you something unique.
我想給你看一些獨特的東西。
My mother would be very pleased to meet you. Come
我媽媽會很高興見到你。來
Raj!
拉吉！
Rita!
麗塔！
You? - After twelve years.
您？ - 經過12年。
You've changed!
你變了！
You haven't changed at all.
您還沒有根本改變。
Where have you been, Raj?
你去哪裡了，拉吉？
Looking for you.
尋找你。
And at last, I've found you - And when I saw you...
而在最後，我找到了你 - 當我看見你...
I took you for a thief.
我把你的小偷。
Not your fault. It's in my looks.
不是你的錯。它在我的長相。
Raj!
拉吉！
"Since my beloved came home, my heart flutters."
“自從我親愛的回家，我的心便紛飛”。
"The heart had spoken to a heart."
“那是心對心的話語。”
"The old times have come back."
“少兒時光又回來了。”
"He brought the happiness with him, my heart flutters."
“他帶來了快樂, 和他在一起，我的心飄揚。”
"Since my beloved came home, my heart flutters."
“自從我親愛的回家，我的心紛飛”。
"From the eyes, he dwelled in my heart."
“他的眼睛，在我的心里打轉。”
"I smile and scatter the stars."
“我微笑，撒星星。”
"Feelings dance and sing, my heart flutters."
“感覺像跳舞，唱歌，我的心紛飛。”
"Since my beloved came home,
“自從我親愛的回家，我的心紛飛”。
"The days belong to us and love is young."
“那日子屬於我們,那愛也是年輕。”
"My world is flourishing due to him."
“我的世界紛飛飄揚，是由於他。”
"The thief returned to my heart, my heart flutters."
“是偷還給我的心，我的心飄揚。”
"Since my beloved came home,
“自從我親愛的回家，我的心紛飛”。
The Judge is here.
法官是在這裡。
So here you are. And you're late.
所以，你在這裡。而你遲到了。
The doctor has told you to come home and rest for at least an hour.
醫生告訴你回家休息至少一個小時。
But you won't listen. You look so tired.
但你不會聽。你看起來很累。
Hello, Rita. - Hello, Rita!
你好，麗塔。 - 你好，麗塔！
Just sit here. I'll get you your dressing gown.
坐在這裡。我給你拿你的晨衣。
Tell me, where have you been all this time?
告訴我，你到哪裡去了這麼長的時間？
I had a lecture in the law college. I went there directly from the court.
我在法學院的演講。我去那裡直接從法庭。
All that jabbering is giving me a headache.
所有這一切是嘰嘰喳喳讓我很頭疼。
That's bound to happen. The doctor told you to eat before eight.
這是必然會發生。醫生告訴你八點前吃。
It's nine thirty now.
它現在九點半。
Listen to that! Even the clock is angry with you.
聽那個！就連鐘​​生你的氣。
Come on.
來吧。
Tell me about yourself. What have you been up to all evening?
說說你自己。你一直到晚上都？
You look as if you've found a treasure.
你看，如果你已經發現了寶藏。
You could say that. A long-lost friend is no less than a treasure.
你可以那樣說。久違的朋友只不過是一個寶藏少。
You'll be glad when you meet Raj. You're certain to like him!
當你遇到拉吉，你會很高興。你一定會喜歡他！
Who is this Mr. Raj? Where does he live? What does he do? What's his family name?
這是誰的拉吉先生？他住在哪裡？他是做什麼的？什麼是他的姓？
He's a childhood friend. We were in school together.
他是一個兒時的朋友。我們在學校在一起。
I'm seeing him after twelve years!
我看到了他十二年後！
After twelve years?
十二年後？
After so many years, most people change.
經過這麼多年，大多數人的變化。
Raj has changed too. At school, he used to be very quiet.
拉吉也發生了變化。在學校裡，他曾經是非常安靜。
Now he has great sense of humour. When I asked him what he's up to...
現在他很有幽默感。當我問他什麼，他是給...
he said he's a thief.
他說他是一個小偷。
Maybe that wasn't a joke? - I don't follow you.
也許這不是一個笑話嗎？ - 我不跟著你。
Never mind.
沒關係。
You know what young men are like, these days.
你知道什麼是年輕人都很喜歡，這幾天。
Who knows, they might steal something valuable.
誰知道，他們可能竊取一些有價值的東西。
The water is deep. You might drown.
水是很深。你可能會被淹死。
Not without you - Is that so? Try that.
沒有你 - 是這樣的嗎？嘗試。
Is that so?
是這樣嗎？
Hey lady, haven't you finished dressing yet?
嘿，小姐，有沒有你穿好衣服了嗎？
Where are you headed? Gentlemen don't barge in...
你要到哪裡去？君子不闖進...
when ladies are changing dresses. Don't you know that?
當女士們正在改變服裝。難道你不知道嗎？
How would I know?
我怎麼會知道？
I'm no gentleman. - Savage.
我不是紳士。 - 野人。
Savage.
野人。
I'm not about to give in to your type.
我不會給您的類型。
Where are you running away?
你在哪裡逃跑？
Let go of my hand. What kind of a stupid joke is this?
放開我的手。什麼樣的愚蠢的笑話的，這是？
You savage!
你野蠻！
Am I? - Yes! You're a savage!
我是誰？ - 是的！你是個野蠻人！
Savage? I'm a penniless, uneducated tramp!
野人？我是一個身無分文，沒有受過教育的流浪漢！
I don't fit into high society!
我不屬於上流社會！
How dare I maul your fragile body with my beastly hands.
我怎麼敢打傷你脆弱的身體和我的獸手中。
I told Ma that childhood friends, like childhood days are gone...
我跟馬雲兒時的朋友，就像小時候日子已經一去不復返了......
never to return.
再也沒有回來。
Good of you to have told me my class.
好你告訴我我的課。
It was a joke. Don't get angry.
這是一個笑話。不要生氣。
You want to hit me? Go ahead.
你想打我？前進。
Whom will I hit?
人將我打？
You?
您？
Or myself?
還是我自己？
Hey! Hey!
嘿!嘿!
Are you happy?
你快樂嗎？
No.
沒有。
Where are you lost? - Up there
你在哪裡失去了什麼？ - 在上面
Come back. - Where to?
回來。 - 去哪兒？
Beside me. - Why?
在我旁邊。 - 為什麼？
No reason.
沒有理由。
Aren't you ashamed?
難道你不感到羞恥？
What are you looking at? The Moon?
你在看什麼？月亮？
No. Clouds.
雲號。
What's your problem? You don't see the Moon...
你怎麼了？你看不到月亮...
and you see the dark clouds? Won't you tell me?
你看到的烏雲？你不告訴我？
Who else can I tell?
我還有誰知道？
Rita. - Yes.
麗塔。 - 是的。
We're seeing each other after twelve years.
我們十二年後看到對方。
So what?
所以呢？
A lot changes in twelve years. - The Judge said that too!
很多十二年變化。 - 法官說呢！
But I don't agree. Look at us. We're still friends.
但我不同意。看著我們。我們還是朋友。
The Judge is right. You know nothing about me.
法官是正確的。你什麼都不知道關於我的。
Who I am...
我是誰...
My circumstances...
我的情況...
My family background...
我的家庭背景......
What I have been doing... what I am doing.
我一直在做......我在做什麼。
You know nothing about me. - Nor do I want to know.
你什麼都不知道關於我的。 - 我也不想知道。
All I know is that you are the one I...
我所知道的是，你是一個我...
Rita, you are so nice. But so naive.
麗塔，你這麼漂亮。但天真。
And you're such a fool. A savage.
你真是個傻瓜。野蠻。
I'm not talking to you.
我不是說你。
Look.
看。
The clouds?
雲？
They are moving away from my Moon.
他們從我的月球逐漸遠離。
You know, today's my birthday.
你知道嗎，今天是我的生日。
Which? Tenth? Eleventh?
哪一個？第十？第十一？
You don't ask a lady that.
你不問女士說。
All right, I'll whisper it to you.
好吧，我要把它悄悄告訴你。
Twenty one.
二十一。
No! It's looking at us.
沒有！它看著我們。
What? - That!
什麼？ - 那！
"Turn your face away for a moment."
“把你的臉離開了一會兒。”
"Turn your face away for a moment, O moon."
“把你的臉走了一會兒，Ö月亮。”
"I will love him."
“我會愛他。”
"I will talk to him about thousand things."
“我會和他談談千元的東西。”
"Turn your face away for a moment, O moon."
“把你的臉走了一會兒，澳月亮。”
"I will love him."
“我會愛他。”
"I will talk to him about thousand things."
“我會和他談談千元的東西。”
"The heart worships love."
“在心臟崇拜的愛。”
"And even I am with him."
“甚至我和他在一起。”
"The stars look at the moon everyday..
“星星盼月亮每天在..
..but this is my first night."
..但是這是我的第一個晚上。“
"My first night."
“我的第一個晚上。”
"Go and hide in the clouds, O moon."
“去和隱藏在雲霧中，澳月亮。”
"I will love him."
“我會愛他。”
"I will talk to him about thousand things."
“我會和他談談千元的東西。”
"Turn your face here for a moment."
“把你的臉在這裡了一會兒。”
"Turn your face here for a moment, O moon."
“把你的臉在這裡了一會兒，澳月亮。”
"I will love her."
“我會永遠愛她。”
"I will lock eyes with her."
“我將目光鎖定了她。”
"I am a thief, my work is to steal."
“我是小偷，我的工作就是偷。”
"I have a bad name in the world."
“我在世界上的名聲。”
"I have been stealing hearts, this is my work."
“我一直在心中偷，這是我的工作。”
"This is my work."
“這是我的工作。”
"You come as a witness, O moon."
“你來當證人，澳月亮。”
"I will love her."
“我會永遠愛她。”
"I will lock eyes with her."
“我將目光鎖定了她。”
"Don't get lost after stealing my heart."
“別偷我的心臟後會丟失。”
"Don't forget the path."
“不要忘了道路。”
"Under these feet don't crush, the flower of my heart."
“在這樣的腳不粉碎，我的心臟的花。”
"The flower of my heart."
“我的心臟的花。”
"Explain this to him, O moon."
“這個解釋給他，哦月亮。”
"I will love him."
“我會愛他。”
"I will talk to him about thousand things."
“我會和他談談千元的東西。”
"Turn your face here for a moment, O moon."
“把你的臉在這裡了一會兒，澳月亮。”
"I will love her."
“我會永遠愛她。”
"I will lock eyes with her."
“我將目光鎖定了她。”
"Turn your face away for a moment."
“把你的臉離開了一會兒。”
One step more, and the boat will turn over and sink.
一步多了，船會翻沉沒。
So what?
所以呢？
Let the boat sink.
讓船下沉。
Rita!
麗塔！
Yes.
是。
Judge sir!
法官先生！
I don't want it - But the doctor says...
我不希望它 - 但醫生說...
I should eat by eight.
我應該八分飽。
Tonight, it's my turn to be admonished by the clock.
今晚，輪到我受時鐘訓誡。
You are angry with me, aren't you?
你是生我的氣，是不是？
Today I was...
今天我是......
With Raj? - Raj is no stranger.
隨著拉吉？ - 拉吉並不陌生。
He's a childhood friend.
他是一個兒時的朋友。
I..
一世..
I made a promise to your dying father.
我做了一個承諾，你垂死的父親。
To take care of you as long as I live.
為了照顧你，只要我活著。
You must make a promise.
你必須做出承諾。
If someone likes you, if you like someone...
如果有人喜歡你，如果你喜歡的人......
...you will not give your consent without telling me.
......你會不會瞞著我給你的同意。
I know, I am much obliged to you.
我知道，我非常感激你。
But it doesn't mean that you can, time and again...
不過，這並不意味著你就可以了，一次又一次......
Boss?
老闆？
Recognise me? Thank you very much!
認不出我？非常感謝你！
You haven't much time nowadays.
你現在沒有多少時間了。
Well son, are you falling in love?
好兒子，你在戀愛？
Or, have you given up your profession for fear of going to jail?
或者，你因為怕坐牢放棄了你的職業？
You don't know the size of the scam I've planned for you.
你不知道我已經打算為你的騙局的大小。
She's an heiress. Just wait for a few days.
她是一個繼承人。只是等待幾天。
I'm angling for a diamond necklace. - Bravo!
我釣了一條鑽石項鍊。 - 好樣的！
I knew it! You aren't the type to waste your time.
我就知道！你是不是浪費你的時間的類型。
But remember!
但要記住！
If you try to cheat Jagga...
如果你試圖欺騙Jagga ...
'Nor do I want to know. All I know is that you are the one I...'
“我也不想知道。我所知道的是，你是一個我......“
'Really?'
'真？'
'Remember! If you try to cheat Jagga...'
'記得！如果你試圖欺騙Jagga ......“
"Without you this moonlight is like fire."
“如果沒有你這個月光像火。”
"Do come."
“你來了。”
"The flute is not melodious without you."
“長笛是不是沒有你悠揚。”
"This life of mine is a melody of pain."
“我的這種生活是痛苦的旋律。”
"Do come."
“你來了。”
"This is not life, this is not life."
“這不是生命，這是沒有生命的。”
"This is not life."
“這不是生活。”
"I am burning alive in this fire of life."
“我在這場大火的生活活活燒死。”
"The arrows of fire run through me."
“火的箭穿過我跑。”
"I don't want this hell."
“我不想要這個地獄。”
"I want the flower, the love, the friend."
“我想花，愛情，朋友。”
"I want the spring."
“我希望的春天。”
"Om Namah Shivay."
“嗡那瑪哈Shivay”。
"Om.."
“嗡......”
"My foreigner has returned home."
“我的老外已經回到了家。”
"The thirst in my eyes is quenched."
“在我眼裡的渴望淬火”。
"You are the pearl of my heart."
“你是我的心臟上的明珠”。
"You are the light of my eyes."
“你是我眼中的光。”
"You are the remembrance of my childhood."
“你是我童年的記憶。”
"My foreigner has returned home."
“我的老外已經回到了家。”
"Now don't go away breaking my heart."
“現在走不走破我的心臟。”
"Don't leave me crying."
“不要離開我哭了。”
"You are under the oath of my tears"
“你是我的眼淚下的誓言”
"My foreigner has returned home."
“我的老外已經回到了家。”
Rita!
麗塔！
Mother! Mother, save me. Mother! - Raju!
母親！媽媽，救我。母親！ - 拉朱！
Ma, I want to be good!
媽，我想好！
I promise, I won't have anything to do with Jagga and those others!
我保證，我不會有任何與Jagga和別人！
I'd rather starve than steal. I will be good.
我寧願餓死也不偷。我會很好。
People will say I'm honest! Let's go back to our slum.
人們會說我是誠實的！讓我們回到我們的貧民窟。
I'll work hard for a living. I won't steal! Ma, I won't steal!
我會為生活打拼。我不會偷！媽，我不會偷！
I want nothing but peace of mind, and my mother's blessings.
我想無非是平和的心態，和我母親的祝福。
I won't steal, Ma. I'll become honest.
我不會偷馬。我會變得老實。
Thank you.
謝謝。
Yes, sir? - You're fired. We won't need you.
是的先生？ - 你被開除了。我們不會需要你。
What? - Go away, get out!
什麼？ - 滾開，滾蛋！
We don't employ thieves.
我們不僱用小偷。
As you wish.
如你所願。
May I ask something, sir? You say you don't want to employ thieves?
請問什麼，先生？你說你不想僱傭盜賊？
Would you rather that they keep thieving all their lives?
你願意，他們一直在竊取他們的生活？
Get out!
出去！
Raj! Raj!
拉吉！拉吉！
Fired? Come on, the boss is calling you.
被解僱？來吧，老闆叫你。
Raj, what reply do I carry back to the boss?
拉吉，什麼答复我帶回給老闆？
This..
這個..
He will either steal or he will starve.
他要么偷不然他會餓死。
And how long will he not steal? He has no way out of crime.
多久他會不會偷？他沒有辦法出來作案。
Let me see how far he goes.
讓我看看他去多遠。
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡？
To see Rita. - You can't go in. The Judge's orders.
看到麗塔。 - 你不能在法官的命令。
The Judge's orders?
法官的命令？
Then go and tell her that Raj is waiting out here to see her.
然後去告訴她，拉吉正在等待在這裡見到她。
I have much to tell her. - She can't see anyone. Get going.
我有很多要告訴她。 - 她看不到任何人。走了。
Get going? Where to?
趕快走？去哪兒？
Come friend.
來吧朋友。
Let me talk to you.
讓我跟你說話。
Strange coincidence, isn't it? You're a tramp, I'm a tramp too.
奇怪的巧合，不是嗎？你是一個流浪漢，我是一個流浪漢了。
You have no name, I have no name either.
你有沒有名字，我沒有名字無論是。
You are homeless, I have no home either.
你是無家可歸的，我沒有家無論是。
Like me, you too crave for love.
像我一樣，你也渴望愛情。
Difference being only that you are an animal, and I'm human.
唯一的區別是，你是一個動物，我很人性化。
Human.
人類。
I have nothing to give you.
我沒有什麼給你。
I can only give love.
我只能給愛。
Why don't you watch your step? Are you blind?
你為什麼不看你的腳步？你瞎了嗎？
Mind your tongue. Bloody savage.
當心你的舌頭。血腥野蠻。
Savage... am I a savage?
野人......我是一個野蠻人？
Am I a mongrel on the streets? To be kicked at will or whim?
我是在街上雜種？隨意或心血來潮被踢？
Piano-fixer?
鋼琴定影液？
Your servant thinks I'm here to fix the piano.
你的僕人認為我到這裡來修復鋼琴。
"Please come now, my desires are squirming."
“請你來，我的渴望蠕蠕”。
"Now the night is about to pass."
“現在夜晚即將過去。”
"I lie crying here, you are silent there."
“我趴在這裡哭，你卻在那沉默。”
"The brightness of the moon is fading."
“月光正在退去。”
"Even the hearts of stars are vanishing. Vanishing."
“星光也在消失，在消失。”
"The fervent ambiance is painful."
“熱切的渴望是痛苦的。”
"Now the night is about to pass."
“現在夜晚即將過去。”
"In the palanquin of the moon."
“月亮的花轎。”
"Where is the bride of night going to? Where is she going?"
“夜的新娘去哪裡？她去哪兒？”
"Even the fate is about to sleep."
“命運將要睡著。”
"You do not arrive, where will I go?"
“你不來，我去哪裡呢？”
"Now the night is about to pass."
“現在夜晚即將過去。”
Rita.
麗塔。
The invitations have been printed.
邀請函已打印。
The day after tomorrow is your birthday, isn't it?
後天是你的生日，不是嗎？
Send them to the friends you want to invite.
它們發送到你想邀請的朋友。
All my friends?
我所有的朋友？
Yes, all friends. All, who are worthy of being your friends.
是的，所有的朋友。所有，誰是值得做你的朋友。
Your birthday.
你的生日。
Raj, aren't you giving me a gift?
拉吉，你不給我一個禮物嗎？
I didn't have money to buy anything. I'll give you some other time.
我沒有錢購買任何東西。我給你一些其他的時間。
Must you only buy something to make a gift?
你一定要只買東西，使一個禮物嗎？
You can give me a flower.
你可以給我一朵花。
Someday, I'm going to make lots of money.
有一天，我會賺很多錢。
And I'll buy a gift for you. Something better than all this.
我會買禮物給你。東西比這個要好。
Back? I knew someday, you'd surely come back.
背部？我知道有一天，你一定會回來。
For you, this is the only door open.
對你來說，這是唯一的門打開。
I need a thousand. A loan I'll return it after I've earned it.
我需要上千人。貸款我將回到它，我已經贏得了上去。
Loan? What d'you think I am, a money-lender?
貸款？你以為我是什麼德，一個放債人？
Today is Rita's birthday. Look, she has invited me.
今天是麗塔的生日。你看，她已經邀請了我。
She takes me for a gentleman. - So you must dress like a gentleman.
她把我的紳士。 - 所以，你必須穿得像個紳士。
And to prove yourself, you must also make a gift to the lady.
為了證明自己，你還必須做一個禮物給女士。
So gentlemanliness is for sale, and you intend buying some?
所以紳士風度是出售，並打算購買一些？
But to become a gentleman, you need money. One thousand Rupees.
但要成為一個紳士，你需要錢。千盧比。
For that thousand, you have to steal, rob, or maybe even kill someone for me.
對於千，你要偷，搶，或者甚至殺人我。
Do you accept? - No.
你接受嗎？ - 號
No! I won't rob! I won't commit crimes!
沒有！我不會來搶！我不會犯的罪行！
What other way out have you?
還有什麼其他出路，是嗎？
Once a criminal, you can never become a gentleman again!
一旦犯罪，你永遠不能再成為一個紳士！
No matter how many times you change your clothes.
不管你有多少次改變你的衣服。
Crime is written all over your face! You even tried working.
犯罪被寫在你的臉上！你甚至嘗試過的工作。
Not for you, the bread in the sweat of thy face.
不適合你，在你臉上的汗麵包。
For you, the only resort is thieving, crime.
對你來說，唯一的辦法就是偷竊，犯罪。
Same as mine!
和我一樣！
All thanks to your father.
這一切都歸功於你的父親。
Watch your step, son.
注意腳下，兒子。
I try. But what to do? Out on the streets...
我試試。但要做到什麼呢？在街頭...
...there are those big guns like you. - Sharp, are you?
...有你這樣的大槍。 - 夏普，是嗎？
Wow Dewan sir, how nicely you said!
哇有得玩先生，怎麼好聽你說！
Have you seen Rita?
你見過麗塔？
I will show you.
我給你看。
"He is a jolly good fellow."
“他是一個極好的夥伴。”
"And so say all of us."
“所以說，我們所有的人。”
"Hip Hip Hip Hip Hurray."
“髖髖華友世紀。”
"He is a jolly good fellow."
“他是一個極好的夥伴。”
"And so say all of us."
“所以說，我們所有的人。”
"Hip Hip Hip Hip Hurray."
“髖髖華友世紀。”
"He is a jolly good fellow."
“他是一個極好的夥伴。”
"And so say all of us."
“所以說，我們所有的人。”
"Hip Hip Hip Hip Hurray."
“髖髖華友世紀。”
"He is a jolly good fellow."
“他是一個極好的夥伴。”
"And so say all of us."
“所以說，我們所有的人。”
"Hip Hip Hip Hip Hurray."
“髖髖華友世紀。”
"He is a jolly good fellow."
“他是一個極好的夥伴。”
"And so say all of us."
“所以說，我們所有的人。”
"Hip Hip Hip Hip Hurray."
“髖髖華友世紀。”
"He is a jolly good fellow."
“他是一個極好的夥伴。”
Tell me something. - What?
告訴我的東西。 - 什麼？
Who are you looking for?
你在找誰？
Want me to tell you?
要我告訴你嗎？
Look, over there.
看那邊。
Raj!
拉吉！
So you came.
所以，你來了。
Happy twenty-first.
快樂二十一。
Your gift. - Why did you have to do this?
你的禮物。 - 你為什麼要這麼做？
Why did you have to buy such an expensive necklace?
為什麼你買這麼昂貴的項鍊呢？
For you, nothing is too expensive. Besides, I stole it.
對你來說，沒有什麼是太貴了。此外，我偷的。
You stole it? - I stole it from the stars.
你偷了嗎？ - 我從星星偷走了。
You're such a... - A savage?
你真是個......  - 野人？
What else? You are a savage.
還有什麼？你是一個野蠻人。
You buy this expensive gift...
你買這個貴重的禮物......
but you won't spend for a velvet case.
但你不會花了天鵝絨情況。
Case?
案件？
Rita, the Judge is calling you. Hurry up.
麗塔，法官叫你。趕快。
Coming.
未來。
What's on your mind?
你在想什麼？
Let me introduce you to the Judge.
讓我把你介紹給法官。
Come on.
來吧。
Rita, I've been waiting for you.
麗塔，我一直在等著你。
First, my present. - See if you like it.
首先，我的存在。 - 看看你是否喜歡它。
Why, don't you like it?
為什麼，你不喜歡嗎？
Today's a strange day. Someone gives me a necklace sans a case.
今天是一個奇怪的一天。他給了我一條項鍊。
And someone give me a case sans the necklace.
而你給我一個項鍊的空匣子。
"I loved a betrayer, I locked eyes with him."
“我喜歡上了一個背叛者，我將目光鎖定在他。”
"O God, what did I do, what did I do?"
“上帝啊，我做了什麼，我做了什麼？”
"A man with an innocent face, turned out to be a thief."
“一張無辜的臉，竟然是個小偷。”
"He hides the darkness inside, but his face is bright."
“他隱藏黑暗在裡面，但臉上卻是光明的。”
"I gave my heart, I made myself fervent."
“我給了我的心，我熱切的心。”
"O God, what did I do, what did I do?"
“上帝啊，我做了什麼，我做了什麼？”
"I loved a betrayer, I locked eyes with him."
“我喜歡上了一個背叛者，我將目光鎖定了他。”
"I was betrayed, by his cobalt blue eyes."
“我被出賣，被他的鈷藍色的眼睛。”
"The cobalt blue eyes."
“鈷藍色的眼睛。”
"The heart is lonely, the eyes are wet."
“我的心是孤獨的，眼睛都濕了。”
"The eyes are wet."
“眼睛都濕了。”
"I trusted him. I proposed my love to him."
“我信任他。我提出我對他的愛。”
"O God, what did I do, what did I do?"
“上帝啊，我做了什麼，我做了什麼？”
"I loved a betrayer, I locked eyes with him."
“我喜歡上了一個背叛者，我將目光鎖定了他。”
Rita, what have you done?
麗塔，你做了什麼？
Fallen in love with a thief?
愛上賊？
And Raju, you?
拉朱和，你呢？
Is it some gift you don't like?
它是一些禮物，你不喜歡？
I'm going to return his gift.
我要回到他的禮物。
Rita.
麗塔。
Bring him over. I'd like to meet him.
帶上他。我想見見他。
Raj isn't a bad boy. He has just gone astray.
拉吉是不是一個壞男孩。他剛誤入歧途。
All he needs is someone to love him, to support him, to bring him around.
所有他需要的是有人愛他，支持他，把他身邊。
He respects you. If you want it, Raj can be saved.
他尊重你。如果你想要的話，拉吉可以保存。
Is Raj not at home? - No. He went out early in the morning.
是拉吉不在家？ - 不，他一大早就出去了。
He isn't back yet.
他尚未恢復。
Okay, mother.
好吧，媽媽。
"By falling in love with you, beloved."
“自從愛上你，親愛的。”
"I kept crying, and I also kept smiling."
“我不停地哭，我也保持著微笑。”
"I happily endure the perils of love."
“我愉快地忍受愛的危險。”
"What do you know the love of the heart!"
“你知道心中的愛！”
"A pain aroused, and my eyes brimmed with tears."
“疼痛，使我的眼睛充滿淚水。”
"My eyes brimmed with tears."
“我的眼睛充滿淚水。”
"But I remained silent."
“但我保持沉默。”
"But I remained silent, I swear on this sadness."
“在這個悲傷時刻，我發誓保持沉默。”
"I kept crying, and I also kept smiling."
“我不停地哭，我也保持著微笑。”
"When the heart burned, there was a fire."
“我心在燒毀，好像發生了火災。”
"When my tears flowed, it rained."
“我的眼淚湧出來，好像下雨。”
"It rained."
“好像下雨。”
"Like a cloud."
“又像雲”。
"Like a cloud, I was a vagabond."
“像雲，我是一個流浪漢。”
"I kept crying, and I also kept smiling."
“我不停地哭，我也保持著微笑。”
"By falling in love with you, beloved."
“自從愛上你，親愛的。”
Raj!
拉吉！
There you are. Haven't you brought the police along?
你在這。沒有你帶警察一起去嗎？
That bitterness is of no use.
苦味是沒有用的。
Your mother has told me everything.
你媽媽告訴了我一切。
So you know I'm vagabond, I've been to jail...
所以，你知道我是流浪漢，我去過監獄...
...and my name is on the police rolls. Is that what you've come to tell me?
......我的名字是對警察卷。是你來什麼來告訴我？
Try to understand me, Raj. I still consider you my friend.
試著理解我，拉吉。我仍然認為你我的朋友。
Friend?
朋友？
A lawyer's daughter, a judge's ward takes a tramp for a friend?
律師的女兒，一個法官的病房需要的朋友流浪漢？
What's your society going to say? What will your people say?
什麼是你的社會會說什麼？什麼將你的人說什麼？
If you recant, society will forgive your past.
如果你放棄信仰，社會會原諒你的過去。
Raj, you can make a new life for yourself... you can!
拉吉，你可以做一個新的生命留給自己......你可以！
A new life? On what will I build a new life?
一種新的生活？在我將要建立一個新的生活？
Can you give me back my childhood, the education I never had?
你能不能給我回我的童年，教育我從未有過？
Everyone says that I have no father to name... I have no honour!
大家都說我沒有父親的名字......我沒有榮幸！
Can you bring my father back? Can you give me my name?
你可以把我的父親回來？你能給我我的名字？
Can you give me my honour? Tell me... tell me Rita!
你能給我我的榮譽？告訴我...告訴我麗塔！
Why are you quiet?
你為什麼要安靜？
Rita, I've kept you in the dark. I've kept myself in the dark.
麗塔，我已經把你在黑暗中。我已經把自己在黑暗中。
Forget me Rita. Leave me to myself.
忘了我吧麗塔。離開我自己。
I am not worthy of you.
我不值得你。
You realise fully well, yet you want to live in this hell.
你意識到完全好了，但你要住在這個地獄。
I never imagined you'd be so weak.
我從來沒有想過你會這麼弱。
Rita, don't you think I never tried to get out of this hell.
麗塔，你不覺得我從來沒有試圖擺脫這種地獄。
But tell me, what do I do?
但告訴我，我該怎麼辦？
For twelve years, the world has chased me towards crime.
十二年，世界已經追我走上了犯罪。
Alone, I cannot face it.
獨自一人，我不能面對它。
Alone, I cannot.
獨自一人，我不能。
You aren't alone, Raj. Your mother is with you.
你並不孤單，拉吉。你媽與你同在。
I'm with you. - You? With me? With a criminal?
我和你在一起。 - 你？跟我？有犯罪？
Yes Raj. With you, forever.
是拉吉。永遠和你在一起。
Good or not, guilty or not, whatever you are, you're mine.
好還是不好，犯與否，不管你是，你是我的。
This is a matter of the heart. And the scales of justice cannot judge it.
這是心臟的問題。和正義的天平無法判斷它。
But this guilt I carry with me forever?
但這種內疚我隨身帶著我一輩子？
For me, as your wife, it will be the bride's vermillion.
對我來說，做你的妻子，這將是新娘的紅唇。
Really?
真？
Come with me. - Where?
跟我來。 - 在哪裡？
The Judge wants to meet you.
法官想見你。
The Judge? - Yes.
法官？ - 是的。
Sit.
坐。
Name?
名稱？
Raj.
拉吉。
Only Raj? - Yes.
只有拉吉？ - 是的。
Your father's name?
你父親的名字？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I see. What do you do?
我懂了。你是做什麼？
As of now, unemployed. Like millions of others.
截至目前，無業。百萬其他人一樣的。
Any other source of income? Property?
任何其他收入來源？屬性？
Nothing.
沒有。
Do you remember polishing boots when you were a boy?
你還記得拋光靴當你還是個孩子？
I still do.
我仍然。
And you want to marry Rita? - Yes. If you allow me.
而你要嫁給麗塔？ - 是的。如果你讓我。
And you've been to jail too? - Rita must've told you that...
你去過監獄嗎？ - 麗塔意有所指告訴你...
You've recanted? Have you found another source of making money?
你已經撤回了？你有沒有發現賺錢的另一個來源？
No. - But there's still hope, isn't it?
號 - 但是仍然有希望，不是嗎？
If some silly rich girl marries you... - Did you call me here to insult me?
如果一些愚蠢的富家女嫁給你......  - 你在這裡罵我侮辱我嗎？
Judge sir..
法官先生..
We are in love.
我們相愛了。
We want to marry. - All that I've heard.
我們要結婚。 - 所有這一切我聽說了。
Love!
愛！
Sit.
坐。
And let's talk it over with a cool head.
讓我們討論一下用冷靜的頭腦。
What do you mean? - I mean that though I don't know...
你什麼意思？ - 我的意思是，雖然我不知道...
..how you managed to seduce a naive girl..
..how你設法勾引天真的女孩..
..it's clear why you played this trick.
..它是清楚為什麼你玩過這一招。
I want to know what price you'll take to let her go.
我想知道你會採取什麼樣的價格讓她去。
Judge Raghunath.
法官拉古納特。
Till today, I thought I was the worst scoundrel on earth.
直到今天，我想我是這個世界上最無賴。
But you turn out to be one up on me!
但是，你練得一上來在我身上！
You scum! How dare you use your filthy colloquy?
你敗類！你怎麼敢用你骯髒的討論會？
You think I'm going to let Rita marry a tramp like you?
你以為我打算讓麗塔嫁給像你這樣的流浪漢？
She'd rather stay a spinster for life. Better by far that she dies!
她寧願留一輩子老處女。迄今為止，她死了更好！
Why not say that you'd rather she married some rich big-shot?
為什麼不說你寧願她嫁給了一些富含大拍？
Or maybe, some judge? - Out of here. Get out.
或者，也許，有些法官？ - 離開這裡。出去。
Before I leave, I'd like to ask you a question.
在我離開之前，我想問你一個問題。
What if it was your son in my place? And because he's poor...
如果這是你在我這裡的兒子？而且因為他是差...
..because he was brought up in the slums and was forced into crime...
..because他自小在貧民窟和被迫犯罪...
...what if it was he who was being denied his love, his life?
......如果這是他誰是被剝奪了他的愛，他的生命？
How would you have felt?
你怎麼會感到？
Raj!
拉吉！
Raj! Raj!
拉吉！拉吉！
Jagga has called you.
Jagga呼籲你。
There's a big heist. A bank is to be looted.
有一個大的搶劫。銀行被洗劫一空。
Open the door!
開門！
Open up. - Who is it?
打開。 - 是誰呀？
Open up!
打開！
Open the door!
開門！
Who is there? - Open the door!
誰在那兒？ - 打開門！
Who are you?
你是誰？
Don't you know me?
難道你不知道我？
I'm Jagga.
我Jagga。
Jagga!
Jagga！
The bandit? - You could say so.
強盜？ - 可以這麼說。
What do you want here? - Silence!
你想要什麼嗎？ - 安靜！
The police are after me. Where's Raj?
警方是在我之後。在哪裡拉吉？
Get out of my house! I will do nothing to help someone like you!
滾出我的房子！我不會做任何事情來幫助別人喜歡你！
I had you once, and I let you go Remember the day?
我擁有了你一次，我讓你走記得那一天？
For twelve years, I cared for your son. I made his life! For this day?
十二年，我照顧你的兒子。我做了他的命！為了這一天？
Made my son's life? You forced him into crime.
讓我兒子的命？你逼他走上了犯罪。
Get out of my house. I don't want your cursed shadow upon my son!
滾出我的房子。我不想讓你詛咒的影子在我的兒子！
Get out! Get out of my house!
出去！滾出我的房子！
Police! Police!
警察！警察！
Go on! Call the police! - Police!
繼續！報警！ - 警察！
Let me see who saves you! Scream!
讓我看看誰可以節省您的！尖叫！
Jagga!
Jagga！
Will you challenge your boss? - You're no boss. You're Satan!
你將挑戰你的老闆？ - 你不是老闆。你是撒旦！
Satan!
撒但！
Let's hear what you have to say now.
讓我們來聽聽你有什麼現在還不好說。
Raj!
拉吉！
Raj! No! No! Mercy!
拉吉！沒有！沒有！憐憫！
No! Enough!
沒有！足夠！
Jagga!
Jagga！
What have you done Raj? - For my sins, this is atonement!
你做了什麼拉吉？ - 為我的罪，這是贖罪！
Police!
警察！
The accused may be presented.
被告可以提出。
What's the name of the accused? - Sir, his name is Raj.
什麼是被告的名字嗎？ - 爵士，他的名字是拉吉。
Father's name? - Not known, sir. Maybe he has none.
父親的名字？ - 不知道，先生。也許他現在沒有。
Order!
訂購！
Raj, you have been accused of killing Jagga.
拉吉，你被指控殺害Jagga。
Do you have anything to say in your defence?
你有什麼在你的防禦要說的嗎？
Have you not appointed a lawyer to defend yourself?
你有沒有委託律師為自己辯護？
The case is adjourned. The government will appoint a counsel for the defence.
案件押後。政府將任命辯護大律師。
I know the law. Raj killed in self-defence. That's no crime.
我懂法律。拉吉自衛打死。這是沒有犯罪。
Please save my Raj, somehow.
請救救我的拉吉，不知何故。
Your deposition is very important. The whole case hinges on it.
你的沉積是非常重要的。全案取決於它。
Come to the court tomorrow. - All right. Okay, dear.
來到法院明天。 - 好吧。好的親愛的。
Husband!
丈夫！
She is unconscious.
她失去知覺了。
Move back! Move! Move!
退後！移動！移動！
Is she dead? - She has been hurt on the head.
她死了？ - 她一直受傷的頭部。
And Raj killed Jagga to save my life.
和Raj殺Jagga救我一命。
Please sign here. This deposition will surely save Raj.
請在這裡簽名。這種沉積必將拯救拉吉。
If Raj is saved, I will be able to die in peace.
如果拉吉被保存，我將能夠在和平中死去。
I should be leaving now.
我現在應該離開。
Mother!
母親！
My son! - What happened to you, Ma?
我的兒子！ - 你怎麼了，媽？
That heartless judge has killed you! What is his enmity with us?
這無情法官殺了你！什麼是他與我們為敵？
You mustn't blame him, son. - Why not?
你不能責怪他，兒子。 - 為什麼不呢？
He has always been tying to make us miserable.
他一直被捆綁讓我們苦不堪言。
No son! He is your father.
沒有兒子！他是你的父親。
My father?
我的父親？
What are you saying, Ma? What has come over you?
你在說什麼，馬？這是怎麼了你？
I'm not out of my mind, son. What I'm saying is the truth.
我不是在我心裡，兒子的。我想說的就是這個道理。
I could not bring myself to tell you this until now.
我不能讓自己來告訴你這個到現在為止。
But if not today, once I'm gone who else could tell you?
但是，如果不是今天，當我走了還有誰可以告訴你嗎？
This can't be, Ma! This can never be!
這是不可能的，馬！這絕不可能！
This is a long story. But I don't have the time.
這是一個很長的故事。但我沒有時間。
Keep this. I'm leaving.
保持這個。我走了。
He will surely recognise you when you show him this.
他一定會承認你，當你告訴他這一點。
He has never forgiven me.
他從來沒有原諒我。
But he will surely forgive his son.
但他肯定會原諒他的兒子。
I won't seek mercy from the one who tortured my mother all her life...
我不會從誰折磨我的母親她所有的生活一個尋求憐憫...
..the one who made her beg from door to door. I won't have his mercy!
..the一個誰做了她乞求從門到門。我不會有他的憐憫！
Ma, I won't have his mercy!
媽，我不會有他的憐憫！
If I could see him for once before I died...
如果我能看到他為我死過一次...
But why would he come here.
但是他為什麼會來這裡。
Come. - I'm leaving Ma.
來。 - 我要離開馬。
Son!
兒子！
I'll avenge you, I will. - No!
我會為你報仇的，我會的。 - 不！
I'll surely avenge you, I will. - No, son!.
我一定會為你報仇的，我會的。 - 不，兒子！
Son!
兒子！
The Judge is here to see you.
法官是在這裡見到你。
Which Judge? - The one whose car ran you over.
哪位法官？ - 在一個其車跑了你。
So he has come... before I'm dead.
於是，他來了......之前我已經死了。
Alas, I cannot see.
唉，我看不到。
Nurse, give him my greetings.
護士，我向他致以問候。
I am ashamed about the accident. Please forgive me.
我很慚愧這次事故。請原諒我。
Forgive you?
原諒你？
Doctor!
醫生！
Mother!
母親！
You didn't die! You were killed!
你沒死！你被打死！
That heartless judge has killed you! To make sure that he isn't exposed!
這無情法官殺了你！為了確保自己不被暴露！
Judge sir!
法官先生！
Have you decided the verdict about the case?
你有沒有決定對案件判決？
Case? - Raj's case.
案件？ - 拉吉的情況。
You are going mad! What are you doing to yourself?
你要瘋了！你在做什麼你自己？
You are a mature, educated woman.
你是一個成熟的，有教養的女人。
In a few days, you'll start going to court as a lawyer.
再過幾天，你就會開始打官司的律師。
You might even make a judge. If you get emotional over every case...
你甚至可能使法官。如果你克服任何情況下情緒...
..you will never be able to dispense justice.
..你將永遠無法伸張正義。
This is not a lawsuit. It's my life!
這不是一場官司。這是我的生活！
Do you not understand as much? - Irrespective, it won't alter the law.
難道你不明白為多少？ - 不論，它不會改變的規律。
Nor should you let your emotions come in the way of justice.
你也不應該讓進來正義的方式你的情緒。
Justice is all I seek. Raj is completely innocent.
正義是我所追求的。拉吉是完全無辜的。
He killed Jagga tying to save his mother.
他殺死了綁Jagga救他的母親。
You can read his mother's dying declaration.
你可以閱讀他的母親的臨終聲明。
In this particular case, Raj might merit pardon.
在這種特殊情況下，可能會拉吉值得原諒。
But his whole life is a long story of involvement with crime and sin.
但是，他的一生是犯罪和罪惡的漫長故事。
I cannot comprehend how you can sympathise with such a person.
我無法理解你怎麼能有這樣的人同情。
How can you love him?
你怎麼能愛他嗎？
You have studied the law.
你學過法律。
But my heart has not read the laws.
但我的心臟已經不讀法律。
Heart... and the laws.
心臟......和法律。
The laws... and the heart.
法律...和心臟。
What a strange concoction.
有什麼奇怪的藥汁。
But you are right.
但是，你是對的。
The heart heeds no laws.
該心臟一概毫不介意沒有法律。
No laws at all.
沒有法律可言。
Not even mine.
連我的。
No! - Get out, Rita.
沒有！ - 下車後，麗塔。
I'm in a murderous rage! - Have you gone mad?
我在暴怒！ - 你瘋了？
So you have escaped? - Yes.
所以，你已經越獄？ - 是的。
To settle the score with you.
與你算帳。
Raj..
拉吉..
Then you will be happy to know that your lawyer...
然後，你會很高興地知道，你的律師......
...had just convinced me about your innocence.
......剛剛說服了我你的清白。
I was inclined to let you off tomorrow.
我傾向於讓你過明天。
I want no mercy from you.
我想從你毫不手軟。
I don't want your justice, your law, nothing!
我不希望你的正義，你的法律，沒有什麼！
All I want...
我所想要的...
Lost your nerve? You need guts to kill someone.
失去了你的神經？您需要膽量殺人。
You should be thanking the one who has just saved your life.
你應該感謝誰剛剛救過你的命的人。
What if I were to use this very knife to rip your heart out?
如果我是用這個非常的刀撕裂你的心臟了呢？
What else can the verdict of the courts be?
還有什麼可以法院的判決呢？
Judge Raghunath was compelled to kill a criminal to save his own life.
拉古納特法官被迫殺人犯罪挽救自己的生命。
Have you gone out of your mind too? - I was. For a second.
你出門不在你的心呢？ - 我曾是。對於第二個。
For the scum that he is, the hangman's noose will be better.
對於他是人渣，劊子手的絞索會更好。
Raj. Raj.
拉吉。拉吉。
This is the story of Raj's life and crimes.
這是拉吉的生活和犯罪的故事。
Now you know why and how he took to crime.
現在你知道為什麼，他如何走上犯罪。
My Lord, the one who is guilty is his father...
我的主，誰是有罪的是他的父親......
..who drove an innocent woman from his house, and denied his own son.
..who開車從他家一個無辜的女人，並否認自己的兒子。
He is the one who forced them to go begging from door to door.
他是誰強迫他們去從門求乞的人。
And in the company of criminals, he went astray.
而在該公司的罪犯，他誤入歧途。
My Lord and members of the Jury...
我的主評審委員會委員...
..if Raj is to be punished for his crime..
..如果拉吉是要懲罰他的罪行..
..then his father should be punished too.
..then他的父親也應該被處罰。
My Lord, I would like to say something.
我的主，我想說點什麼。
Emotion has got the better of the counsel for defence.
情緒已經拿到了律師辯護的更好。
In her anxiety to save the accused, the counsel has presented...
在她的焦慮，以節省被告人，辯護律師已提出...
..an interesting story, however incongruous it might be...
..an有趣的故事，但不協調的可能是...
..to try and prove that some criminal happens to be my son!
..to試圖證明一些犯罪恰好是我的兒子！
But I ask, what evidence does the counsel have?
但我要問，律師有什麼證據？
No evidence on earth will convince you that Raj is your son...
世界上沒有任何證據將說服你，拉吉是你的兒子......
..not unless you are willing to accept him as your son.
..not除非你願意接受他成為你的兒子。
If there be proof, it lies deep in your heart and in Raj's eyes.
如果真有那麼證明，而在於你的心臟和Raj的​​眼神深邃。
Look at him. The same eyes, the same high brow.
看著他。同樣的眼睛，同樣的高額頭。
He even speaks like you speak. He's just as adamant as you are.
他甚至說像​​你說話。他只是作為堅定的你。
Are you still not willing to accept him as your son?
你還是不願意接受他為你的兒子？
Ms Rita, the law heeds no emotion.
麗塔女士，法律一概毫不介意沒有任何表情。
Nor my Lord, does the heart heed any law.
也不是我的主，請問心臟聽從任何法律。
I have no more to say.
我沒有多說。
If the accused has anything to say in his defence, he may proceed.
如果被告有任何為他辯護說，他可能會繼續進行。
Yes. At last, after being branded a murderer...
是。最後，後被打成殺人犯...
..I hold your attention.
..我握住你的注意力。
Had I been heard earlier, perhaps I would never have had to stand here.
要是我早有所聞，也許我永遠不會有站在這裡。
Ms Rita has tried her best to save me from being hanged.
麗塔女士已經盡了力救我被絞死。
And not only in this particular case; in my personal life too.
而且不只是在這種特殊情況下，在我的個人生活了。
In my defence, I wish to say nothing. I am evil.
在我的防守，我想說什麼。我很邪惡。
I've been a vagabond ever since I was a child.
我去過一個流浪漢自從我還是個孩子。
I'm a murderer, a criminal.
我是一個殺人犯，一個犯罪。
You may punish me as you please. But sin, crime, hatred and violence...
請你，你會懲罰我。然而罪，犯罪，仇恨和暴力...
..this vicious circle that holds your society in a vice-grip...
..this保存你的社會一個副握惡性循環......
..do you think it can be broken by hanging me?
..do你認為它可以通過吊箱被打破？
I don't want to tell you the story of my life.
我不想告訴你我的生活的故事。
But all I want to say is, I did not inherit crime from my parents.
但我想說的是，我沒有從我的父母那裡繼承遺產的罪行。
From that gutter full of filth that flows beside my shanty...
從陰溝裡充滿污穢，我的旁邊棚戶流...
...I picked up crime. That gutter is still flowing over.
......我拿起罪。這陰溝裡仍然流過。
And the virus still breeds.
而病毒仍然孕育。
And countless children who live in those slums...
和無數的孩子誰住在貧民窟裡的那些...
..are falling prey to the virus every day.
..are每天墮入病毒。
Do not think of me. Those children are the ones you must care for.
不要以為我。這些孩子是你必須照顧的人。
You must care for your children.
你必須照顧你的孩子。
Lest come the day when... yours...
免得來的一天，當你... ...
..and yours...
..和你的...
..and your son too stands in these docks to reiterate...
..和你的兒子太矗立在船塢這些重申...
..that it's an honest father's blood that flows in my veins.
..that這是一個誠實的父親的血，流在我的血管。
Time was when I was an innocent boy, just like your sons.
一次是當我是一個無辜的孩子，就像你的兒子。
Like all mothers, my mother too wove a golden dream for me.
像所有的母親，我的母親也編織一個金色的夢我。
She would say, "My son will grow up to become a lawyer".
她會說，“我的兒子長大後成為一名律師。”
Then he will become a magistrate. And then, a judge... like his father.
然後，他將成為一個縣令。然後，法官......像他的父親。
I know the verdict that this court is about to give.
我知道判決結果，這個法院要放棄。
And I'm willing to suffer any sentence. For my sins, this is atonement.
而且我願意承受任何判決。為我的罪，這是贖罪。
But I await the decision from yet another quarter.
但我在等待著從另一個季度的決定。
I want to know Judge Raghunath, what says your heart?
我想知道拉古納特法官，你的心臟說？
What says your heart?
你的心臟怎麼說？
Raj!
拉吉！
Has the Judge come to see his convict?
有法官來看望他的囚犯？
A father...
一位父親...
..who is guilty.
..who是有罪的。
Guilty? You?
有罪？您？
Yes.
是。
Tomorrow, the law might pronounce you guilty.
明天，法律可能會宣布你們有罪。
But in the eyes of God, I am the one who is guilty.
但在上帝的眼裡，我是一個有罪的。
Are you weeping?
哭？
Yes, for the father who found his son, and yet he has lost him.
是的，誰發現兒子的父親，但他已經失去了他。
For the husband who forced his wife to become a widow.
對於誰逼他的妻子成為寡婦的丈夫。
For society, where poverty breeds crime.
對於社會裡，貧窮滋生犯罪。
For the son who is orphaned though his father is alive.
對於誰是孤立的，雖然他的父親還活著的兒子。
For the child who goes through life looking for someone...
對於誰經歷的生活找人的孩子...
..who will call him "Son".
..who將稱呼他為“兒子”。
Son.
兒子。
Son!
兒子！
Raj, son of Judge Raghunath, you have been proved guilty...
拉吉，拉古納特法官的兒子，你已經被證實有罪......
..of tying to assassinate your father, Judge Raghunath.
..of捆綁刺殺你的父親，拉古納特法官。
But in the light of the strange and unfortunate circumstances your life...
但在陌生的和不幸的情況下你生活中的光...
..which your counsel Ms Rita has presented...
..這你的律師麗塔女士已提出...
..you are sentenced to only three years of rigorous imprisonment.
..你被判處只有三年嚴格的監禁。
Crying?
哭？
You silly girl.
你傻丫頭。
Silly, lawyers never cry.
傻，律師永不哭泣。
At this rate, how are you going to practice?
按照這種速度，你怎麼練？
What use is the practice, Raj? I wasn't able to save you.
有什麼用的做法，拉吉？我沒能救你。
No Rita, this penance is very important for me.
沒有麗塔，這是苦修對我來說很重要。
Only after I've been through this, will I be worthy of you.
我已經通過這只是後，我會對得起你。
With you beside me, I can go through anything.
有了你我的身邊，我可以兩肋插刀。
I will become an honest man.
我將成為一個誠實的人。
Everyone will say I'm a good man.
每個人都會說我是個好人。
I will read, I will write.
我會讀，我會寫。
And just like Ma used to say, first I'll become a lawyer...
就如同馬雲曾經說，首先，我會成為一名律師...
..then a magistrate.
..then裁判官。
And then, a judge.
然後，法官。
Last night I saw a judge. And I liked him.
昨天晚上，我看到了一個判斷。我很喜歡他。
I'll become a judge.
我會成為一名法官。
You won't call me a savage anymore, will you?
你會不會罵我是野蠻了，你願意嗎？
I will. You savage!
我會。你野蠻！
Time up.
時間到。
Come on.
來吧。
Keep this.
保持這個。
It's your gift.
這是你的禮物。
Don't worry. I didn't steal it.
不要擔心。我沒偷。
I just smuggled it in.
我只是偷偷進去。
Raj.
拉吉。
Not your fault, Rita. It's just the way I look.
不是你的錯，麗塔。這只是我的樣子。
Three years isn't too long, Raj. I'll wait for you.
三年不太久，拉吉。我會等你的。
Rita.
麗塔。
I'll wait for you! - Don't cry.
我會等你的！ - 不要哭。
Number 308... move it.
號碼308 ......移動。
I should be.
我應該。
"I'm not flourishing, I am not ruined."
“我不旺，我不是毀了。”
"Still I sing happy songs."
“不過我唱歡歌”。
"My heart is filled with wounds."
“我的心臟充滿了傷口。”
"But still these lively eyes smile."
“但是，這仍然活潑的眼睛微笑。”
"World.."
“世界..”
"World, I am troubled by your sorrows or misfortunes."
“世界，我對你的悲傷和不幸的困擾。”
"I am a vagabond."
“我是流浪者。”